No matter how nuclear war begins, it
无论核战争如何爆发，都将
ends in 72 minutes and 5 billion people
在72分钟内结束，50亿人
would be dead.
将丧生。
Do you think there will be a nuclear
你认为会爆发核
war?
战争吗？
So, I've interviewed former secretaries
所以，我采访了前
of defense, the former nuclear
国防部长、前核潜艇
subcommander, the Secret Service, and
指挥官、特勤局人员，
what I learned was, oh my god.
我了解到的情况是，我的天哪。
Annie Jacobson, investigative researcher
安妮·雅各布森，调查研究员
and writer who specializes in uncovering
兼作家，专门揭露
the world's biggest secrets. We are one
世界最大的秘密。 我们
misunderstanding away from nuclear
距离核
apocalypse. And yet you have presidents
灾难只有一步之遥。 然而，你却看到有总统
threatening nuclear war. In fact, the
威胁要发动核战争。 事实上，
president of the United States doesn't
美国总统根本不需要
need to ask anyone to launch a nuclear
请求任何人发射
missile.
核导弹。
It makes me realize how important the
这让我意识到，
decision to pick our leaders is.
选择领导人是多么重要。
Nothing could be more important.
没有什么比这更重要了。
Could you play out a scenario where
你能设想一下
nuclear war broke out?
核战争爆发的情景吗？   是的
Yes. And I can describe in painstaking
。 我可以极其
horrific detail precisely what happens.
细致地描述所发生的事情。
So,
所以，
but after nuclear war, the survivors
核战争之后，幸存者
would be forced to live underground and
将被迫生活在地下，并
envy the dead.
羡慕死者。
Annie, is there anyone you interviewed
安妮，你采访过的所有人中，有没有谁让
that brought you to tears?
你感动落泪的？   是的
Yes. I met a woman who is a survivor of
。 我遇到了一位
the Nagasaki bomb. And I haven't written
长崎原子弹爆炸的幸存者。 我还没有写过
about this yet,
这件事，
but someone I interviewed and someone
但我采访过的一个人，也是
that meant a lot to me wired that
对我意义重大的人，参与了投掷
nuclear weapon that was dropped on
在
Nagasaki.
长崎的那枚核武器的接线工作。
Can you speak about the impact that it
您能谈谈这件事
had on both those individuals?
对这两个人的影响吗？   太
And it's horrifying.
可怕了。
Congratulations, Dario gang. We've made
恭喜达里奥帮！ 我们取得了
some progress. 63% of you that listen to
一些进展。 经常收听本播客的听众中，有 63%
this podcast regularly don't subscribe,
没有订阅，
which is down from 69%.
这一比例低于之前的 69%。
Our goal is 50%. So, if you've ever
我们的目标是50%。 所以，如果您
liked any of the videos we've posted, if
喜欢我们发布的任何视频，如果
you like this channel, can you do me a
您喜欢这个频道，能否帮我个
quick favor and hit the subscribe
忙，点击订阅
button? It helps this channel more than
按钮？ 这对本频道的帮助比
you know. And the bigger the channel
你想象的要大。
gets, as you've seen, the bigger the
正如你所看到的，频道规模越大，
guests get. Thank you and enjoy this
嘉宾的名气也就越大。 谢谢收看，祝您
episode.
收听愉快。
[Music]
[音乐]
Annie, you wrote this book about nuclear
安妮，你写了一本关于核
war and published it in March 2024.
战争的书，并于2024年3月出版。
little bit coincidental when I or not
当
when I look at what's going on in the
我审视
world at the moment. Why did you write a
当今世界正在发生的事情时，这本书的出版时间似乎有点巧合，也或许并非如此。 你为什么写一本
book about nuclear war
关于核战争的书？
and why did you write it now?
又为什么选择在这个时候写？
As an investigative journalist
作为一名
before nuclear war, a scenario, I had
核战争前的调查记者，我曾
written six previous books, all of which
写过六本书，全部都是
are about the military and intelligence
关于美国的军事和情报
organizations in the United States.
机构的。   美国国防高级研究计划局（
DARPA, Area 51, always the Pentagon, the
DARPA）、51区、五角大楼、
CIA. That's my that's my beat. And think
中央情报局。 这就是我的节奏。 想想
about how many sources I have in each
我每本书里引用了多少参考文献
book. a hundred or more. How many
。 一百个或更多。 顺便说一句，
covering all the wars by the way since
自二战以来，有多少人报道了所有战争
World War II, all these intelligence and
，所有这些情报和
military programs uh intensely kinetic
军事计划都极其活跃，
and think of how many people said to me
想想有多少人
with a kind of pride, I dedicated my
带着某种自豪感对我说，我毕生致力于
life to preventing nuclear World War
防止第三次世界大战的核战争
III. That's always the idea in the
。
Defense Department and in the CIA. We
国防部和中央情报局一贯都是这么想的。 我们的
are there to prevent nuclear war. And so
任务是防止核战争。 因此，在前
former President Trump, there was this
总统特朗普执政期间，出现了这种
presidential rhetoric going on. You may
总统式的言论。 你或许还
recall fire and fury. Trump and the
记得那场烈火与怒火。 特朗普和
president of North Korea, the leader of
朝鲜领导人，也就是
North Korea, threatening this kind of
朝鲜的总统，竟然威胁要采取这种
thing. And I like many I'm sure began to
行动。 我相信很多人都和我一样开始
wonder my god what if deterrence another
思考，如果威慑（也就是
word for prevention fails
预防）失败了会怎样？
and that is the question that I put to
这也是我向
all of those sources in the book and
书中所有资料来源提出的问题，而
that result is nuclear war a scenario.
结果就是核战争。
What was your intention?
你的目的是什么？
I wanted to show in horrific detail
我想用极其恐怖的细节展现
horrible, just how apocalyptic nuclear
核战争究竟有多么可怕，多么具有世界末日般的破坏力
war will be. Because I think many people
。 因为我认为很多人
have forgotten
已经忘记
or don't know to begin with the
或者根本不知道
consequences of a nuclear exchange. As I
核战争的后果。 正如我
show in the book, almost certainly
在书中指出的，几乎可以肯定的是，
if a nuclear exchange happens, and we're
如果发生核战争（我们
talking strategic ballistic missiles, it
说的是战略弹道导弹），战争将持续
will not stop until the world ends. And
到世界末日才会停止。
we are talking about in seconds and
我们说的是秒和
minutes, not in days and weeks and
分钟，而不是天、周和
months. That is astonishing.
月。 真是令人震惊。
When did you start writing the book?
你什么时候开始写这本书的？
When was the first word written?
第一个字是什么时候写下的？
So, probably during COVID was the first
所以，很可能是在新冠疫情期间写下的第一个
word written. But keep in mind, my
字。 但请记住，我
reporting on nuclear weapons goes back
对核武器的报道贯穿了
my entire career. My first book, Area
我的整个职业生涯。 我的第一本书《
51, is about a a joint CIA air force
51区》讲述的是位于内华达沙漠的一个中央情报局空军联合
base out there in the Nevada desert
基地，这是
inside a secret test and training range
一个秘密的试验和训练场，
where the United States government used
美国政府曾在
nuclear weapons in the 50s. And so my
20世纪50年代在那里引爆核武器和大气层核武器。 所以，
when I was reporting Area 51, I inter I
当我报道51区的时候，我最终
intend to, but I wound up interviewing
采访了
the people who armed, wired, and fired
那些参与核武器的研制、安装和发射的人，
Project members, and they that was kind
也就是曼哈顿计划的早期成员，这完全出乎我的意料。这算是
of my B story of Area 51. And what I
我的51区报道的副线故事。我
learned was like, oh my god. And I was
了解到的情况简直令人震惊。 我
also surprised to learn that most people
还惊讶地发现，大多数人
didn't even know we the American
甚至不知道美国
government set off a hundred some odd
政府曾在内华达州的沙漠中引爆了一百多枚
atmospheric nuclear weapons in the
大气层核武器进行
desert in Nevada testing them. So my
试验。 所以，我的
reporting to answer that's a long-
回答有点
winded answer of I've been on this issue
冗长，因为我多年来一直在间接地关注这个问题，
you know for years for more than a
你知道，已经超过
decade but the idea in this book the
十年了。但这本书里提到的“
word one as you asked was like once I
一”字，就像你问的那样，一旦我
understood that nuclear war is a
理解了核战争是一个
sequence it begins the first fraction of
序列，它在探测到核弹后的第一瞬间就开始了，
a second after detection then I could
然后我就能
see clearly oh my god it's a ticking
清楚地看到，哦，我的天哪，这是一个
clock scenario because it just all
倒计时的场景，因为这一切
happened so fast.
发生得太快了。
I asked that again because so if you
我再次问这个问题，是因为如果你
book on nuclear war in co sort of 2020
在 2020 年左右开始写一本关于核战争的书的第一个字，嗯
Mhm. 2020 roughly 2021
。 大概是2020年到2021年左右，也就是
around there in 2021. Yeah. Since then,
2021年。是的。 自那以后，
things have escalated around the world
世界各地的
in terms of conflict in a way that I
冲突局势急剧升级，我
imagine you couldn't have forecasted.
想这是你无法预料的。   颇具讽刺意味的是，就在
month that your book was published,
你的书出版的那个月，
Putin moved I think he moved nuclear
普京似乎把核武器问题提上了
weapons into Barus and the rhetoric and
日程，
he started saying that he would use
开始发表言论，声称他会使用
them. And if you look at the terminology
核武器。 如果你看看
him and his commanders are using towards
他和他的指挥官们对
the world, it seems like we're at a
世界使用的措辞，就会发现我们正处于一个
moment that I haven't seen in my
我一生中从未见过的时刻，
lifetime where the subject of nuclear
核战争的话题
war seems to be more real than ever
似乎比以往任何时候都更加真实
before.
。
You're absolutely right. And that is
你说得完全正确。 这很令人
astonishing because in 2021 when I began
惊讶，因为在 2021 年我开始
the interviews,
采访的时候，
people were forthcoming with me. You
人们都很坦诚。
know, as you know from the list of
正如你从
sources, I've interviewed former
消息来源列表中了解到的，我采访过前
secretaries of defense, former nuclear
国防部长、前核潜艇
subcommander, you know, former Stratcom
司令、前战略司令部
commander, former FEMA director, former
司令、前联邦紧急事务管理署署长、前
cyber chief. And a lot of these
网络安全主管。
individuals shared with me in 2021 this
2021 年，很多人向我表达了这样一种
idea that wow the world has kind of
想法：哇，世界似乎已经
forgotten that the nuclear threat is
忘记了核威胁
always there. And so over the course of
一直存在。 因此，在
reporting and writing, you're absolutely
报道和写作的过程中，您完全
right that the geopolitical
正确，
temperature of the world has escalated
世界地缘政治温度已经上升
to a point that you have not seen in
到您
your lifetime and I haven't seen in my
和我一生中都未曾见过的程度
lifetime.
。
setting the stage even more. We talked
进一步铺垫剧情。 我们讨论了
about how possible nuclear war is, but
核战争的可能性，但
one thing I learned from reading your
我从你的书中学到的一件事
book, which actually surprised me, was
，着实让我感到惊讶，那就是
to agree on a nuclear war for it to
核战争的爆发并不需要成千上万的人达成共识
begin. In the case of the United States,
。 就美国而言，
it only takes one person to make that
只需要一个人做出这样的
decision, which I find quite unnerving
决定，这让我感到非常不安，因为
that could theoretically make the
理论上只有一个人可以做出
decision that would destroy the earth.
毁灭地球的决定。
You're absolutely right. And this kind
你说得完全正确。
of thing is surprising to almost
几乎所有人都会对这种事情感到惊讶
everyone. One of the things that I
。 我
strive to do in my reporting is take
在报道中努力做到的一点是，将
very complex
非常复杂的
science and technology military issues
科学技术和军事问题
and simplify them down for the layman,
简化成普通人，也就是
just for the average Joe or the average
普通民众能够理解的内容
Jane. And I do that by interviewing
。 我通过采访那些在这些领域
the really smart, really knowledgeable
真正聪明、知识渊博的
people on those subjects. I have two
人来做到这一点。
things going for me perhaps as an
作为一名
investigative journalist that help in
调查记者，我可能有两点优势有助于我
conveying the story is that I'm not a
讲述故事：一是我不是
scientist and so I can ask questions
科学家，所以我可以问一些
that the average person would ask like
普通人会问的问题，比如
really try and help me understand this
真正努力帮助我理解这件事；二是，
whatever this is and then also that I
我
have a real interest in making what is
真心希望
conveyed to me make sense
我所听到的内容能够被
to other people in their lives. Right?
其他人理解。 正确的？
So, and also perhaps make them realize I
所以，或许还能让他们意识到，我甚至从未
never even stopped to think about the
停下来思考过这样一个
fact how strange is it that the United
事实：
States president, this is what you learn
美国总统，正如你
in the book and you're talking about the
在书中学到的，拥有
presidential authority to launch a
发动
nuclear war.
核战争的唯一总统权力，这有多么奇怪。
What does that mean?
这意味着什么？
It's exactly like it sounds. What's so
就是字面意思。 最
interesting is a lot of this stuff, this
有趣的是，很多这些东西，这些
nomenclature that gets thrown at you, if
被抛给你的术语，如果
you just break it down, it's soul solo
你仔细分析一下，就会发现它们其实是灵魂独奏
presidential. He's the pus authority. He
总统。 他是脓液领域的权威。 他
doesn't have to ask anyone for
不需要征求任何人的
permission. Not the sect staff, not the
许可。 不是教派工作人员，不是参谋长
chairman of the joint chiefs of staff,
联席会议主席，
not the congress. I love the worried
也不是国会。 我喜欢
look on your face in this moment because
你此刻脸上担忧的表情，因为
it is once you know that
一旦你知道了这一点，
you say, well, first you might Google,
你就会想，嗯，首先你可能会在谷歌上搜索，
is it really true? And you will get, for
这是真的吗？
example, on Reddit like that's not
例如，在 Reddit 上，你会看到有人说这并非
really true. you'll get like hundreds of
事实。 你会看到
thousands of people, you know, coming in
成千上万的人涌入，发表
with their opinions about how that's not
他们的看法，认为这并非
really true. Well, it is really true.
事实。 确实如此。
It's absolutely true. And in fact,
完全属实。 事实上，在前
during the former President Trump
总统特朗普
administration,
执政期间，
Congress became so sort of I want to say
国会
motivated or alarmed by this issue,
对这个问题变得非常重视，或者说感到担忧，这
meaning they were being asked questions
意味着当权者开始向他们提出问题
by the powers that be. Is this actually
。
true that they released a report stating
他们真的发布了一份报告，其中
specifically and I quote in the book,
明确指出（我在书中引用了这句话）：
"Yes, it is true. As commanderin-chief,
“是的，这是真的。作为三军统帅，
the president has this sole authority.
总统拥有这项至高无上的权力。
He doesn't need to ask anyone."
他不需要征求任何人的意见。”
And hopefully sort of my bringing sort
希望我一开始就把这样的
of concepts like that to the four right
概念带给这四位
away, the reader can then become engaged
读者，他们就能被吸引，然后
and they say, "Well, that's weird. Why?"
说：“嗯，这很奇怪。为什么呢？”
And then I can give you a very simple
然后我可以给你一个非常简单的
answer without necessarily taking you
答案，而不必带你
through the whole history of
回顾总统权力的整个历史
presidential authority, but it has to do
，但这与总统权力的
with the ticking clock of it. And I
时效性有关。 我
explained to you right away that a
立刻就向你解释过了，
ballistic missile travels from one
弹道导弹是从一个
continent. It's called an ICBM. People
大陆发射出去的。 它被称为洲际弹道导弹。 人们
have heard of that intercontinental
都听说过洲际
ballistic missile. Again, exactly like
弹道导弹。 正如字面
it sounds. It can travel from one
意思一样。 它可以携带核弹头，
continent to the next in roughly 30
在大约 30 分钟内从一个大陆飞到另一个大陆，
strike a target. Once you realize, wait
打击目标。 当你意识到这
a minute, there are only 30 minutes.
一点时，等等，只剩下 30 分钟了。
This isn't like, hey guys, should we go
这可不是那种“嘿，伙计们，我们是不是该去
have a war in Iraq? Let's discuss this.
伊拉克打仗？”之类的问题。 我们来讨论一下这个问题。
Let's debate this. Let's take it to the
我们来讨论一下这个问题。 让我们把这件事提交给
Congress. This is there is a ballistic
国会。 先生，有一枚弹道导弹正朝
States and you must act. And that's why
美国袭来，您必须采取行动。 这就是为什么用
in the simplest layman's terms, sole
最简单的通俗语言来说，
presidential authority exists.
存在着总统独断专行的权力。
So let's define then what these weapons
那么，让我们来定义一下这些武器究竟
are. We've many of us have seen that
是什么。 我们很多人都看过那部
film Oppenheimer. We saw them out in the
电影《奥本海默》。
desert I think in New Mexico playing
我想我们曾在新墨西哥州的沙漠里看到他们
playing with all these weapons and
玩弄各种武器，
eventually making this one bomb that
最终制造出一枚炸弹，
they would then drop drop in Japan.
然后他们打算把这枚炸弹投放到日本。
The weapon we see in that film which was
我们在电影中看到的那件武器，是
in the 194 made in the 1940s that
20 世纪 40 年代制造的 194 型步枪，它
ultimately led to the end of the war. Is
最终导致了战争的结束。
that the same weapon that we're talking
这就是我们今天讨论的那种武器吗
about today?
？
No. Well, in in in sort of principle in
不。嗯，某种程度上来说，是
Yes. meaning it's an atomic bomb, but
的。 这意味着它是一颗原子弹，但
there's two things that separate where
有两件事将
we are now. One has to do with the size
我们与现在的情况区分开来。 其中一个因素与
and the power of the bomb. So the the in
炸弹的体积和威力有关。 所以，
1945 there were atomic bombs. Now there
1945年就有了原子弹。 现在有了
are thermonuclear bombs. So an atomic
热核武器。 所以，
bomb is used inside a thermonuclear
原子弹被用作热
weapon as the trigger.
核武器的引爆装置。
Okay,
好吧，
it is a bomb inside a bomb. And the
这是一颗炸弹里还有一颗炸弹。
power of the thermonuclear bomb is so
热核炸弹的威力真是
astonishingly,
惊人，
you know, destructive. You can read the
你知道，破坏力巨大。 您可以查看
details. I interviewed Richard Garwin
详情。 我采访了理查德·加文，
bomb for Edward Teller when he was 24
他24岁时为爱德华·泰勒设计了第一颗热核武器
years old. I interview him, he's in his
。 我采访了他，他已经
90s. He explains to me and I explain to
90多岁了。 他向我解释，我也向
you what the power is behind that. But
你解释这背后的力量是什么。 但这就是
this so the atomic bomb and and it has
原子弹，而且这
to do with size. Like the old atomic
与体积有关。 就像以前的原子弹一样
bomb, the one that was dropped on
，投在
Hiroshima was the size of a small
广岛的那颗原子弹也有一头小
elephant.
象那么大。
Okay. 15 kilotons in a big giant
好的。 一枚15千吨当量的巨型
elephantized bomb inside of an aircraft
象形炸弹，装在一架飞机上，
having to fly from Tinian Island to over
必须从提尼安岛飞到
Hiroshima where it drops in an aircraft.
广岛上空，然后由飞机投下。
when we brought the Nazi scientists to
自从我们把纳粹科学家带过来之后，一切都改变了
us. Oh, let's have let's figure out how
。 哦，我们来想想办法
to do two things. Let's figure out how
做两件事吧。 我们来研究一下如何
to create more powerful bombs. That's
制造威力更大的炸弹。 这就是
the result. The result is the
结果。 结果就是
thermonuclear bomb. And let's make them
热核炸弹。 我们还要把它们做得
smaller. We can't load an elephant-sized
更小。 我们不可能把大象大小的
weapon into the top of a ballistic
武器装进弹道导弹的顶部
missile. It needs to be smaller. And so
。 它需要更小一些。 因此，
so much of this buildup was about
这种大规模的研发部署很大程度上是为了
creating more powerful weapons to be
制造
smaller in size.
体积更小、威力更大的武器。
And then you see the military-industrial
然后你就会看到军工
complex. You you can imagine, and I do
复合体。 你可以想象，我这样做是为了用
this as a history lesson in just a few
短短几页篇幅给读者上一堂历史课，以便让他们
to speed without losing the drama of the
快速了解情况，同时又不失叙事的戏剧性
narrative. And
。
the result, so if you flash forward to
因此，如果我们快进到
where we are now, which is where we've
我们现在所处的位置（也就是我们已经处于这个位置
been for a very long time, is a nuclear
很长时间了），结果就是核
triad, just like it sounds, three parts.
三位一体，正如其名，由三个部分组成。
We have ICBMs, silos under the ground.
我们有洲际弹道导弹，还有地下发射井。
So, those are weapons hidden in the
所以，那些是埋在地下的武器
ground.
。
In the United States, there are 400 of
美国有400个这样的国家
them. There were more. Now, there are
。 还有更多。 现在有
400. You can find out where they are on
400个。你可以在地图上找到它们的位置
a map. They're in silos, underground
。 它们储存在筒仓里，
silos across the Midwest and the West.
遍布中西部和西部的地下筒仓里。
Then we have our nuclear armed,
然后我们还有核动力、携带核弹头的
nuclearpowered submarines that carry
核动力潜艇，它们携带的
that same kind of concept of a ballistic
弹道导弹的概念
missile with a warhead in its nose cone.
与核动力潜艇相同，弹头位于弹头锥内。
We have those same systems on submarines
我们在潜艇上也使用了同样的系统，
and the technology behind it is
其背后的技术令人
astonishing. I take the reader through
惊叹。 我带领读者
it fast from the experts who explain it
快速浏览专家们的讲解，他们
to me in a digestible way. And those
用通俗易懂的方式向我解释了相关内容。 这些
systems lurk around in the oceans all 24
系统
hours a day, 7 days a week, 365 days a
一年365天，一天24小时，一周7天，都潜伏在海洋中
year. They're called the handmaidadens
。 她们被称为
of the apocalypse.
末日使女。
They're almost impossible to find,
它们几乎不可能找到，
right?
对吧？
They are impossible to find. the nuclear
它们根本找不到。
the former nuclear force subcommander
前核部队副司令
um Admiral Connor had this great way of
康纳海军上将曾用一种很形象的方式
describing it to me when I said like how
向我描述过核武器。当我问他
hard is it to find a sub he said Annie
找到一艘潜艇有多难时，他说：“安妮，
object in space
在太空中找到一个柚子大小的物体
than a nuclear sub under the sea
都比在海底找到一艘核潜艇容易。”
and it's not just the United States that
而且，
have these weapons which I think is
拥有这些武器的不仅仅是美国，我认为这一点很
important to say there's many people
重要，现在全世界有很多国家
have these weapons in their country too.
也拥有这些武器。
You list um several of those countries.
你列举了其中几个国家。
I think it's nine countries in total
我认为总共有九个国家
that has nuclear weapons, right?
拥有核武器，对吗？
One of those countries, I know we have
我知道
them back in the UK.
英国就有这样的国家。
Yeah, there are nine nuclear armed
是的，世界上有九个拥有核武器的
nation. Also really interesting to think
国家。
about that the whole sort of let's have
思考“让我们组建一个
a triad. Let's have all these weapons
三人组”这种想法也很有意思。 让我们拥有所有这些武器，
that we will you will have a concept of
这样你们就会明白
mutual assured destruction. So we will
相互确保摧毁的概念。 所以我们会
have these weapons but we will never use
拥有这些武器，但我们永远不会使用
them because everyone would be
它们，因为使用它们会
destroyed. Those concepts go back to the
毁灭所有人。 这些概念可以追溯到
50s when there were only two nuclear
20 世纪 50 年代，当时世界上只有两个拥有核武器的
armed nations, the United States and
国家，即美国和
Soviet Russia. So you know really making
苏联。 所以，你知道，
all of this more precarious talk looping
所有这些更加岌岌可危的讨论最终又回到了
back to your you know notion that like
你之前的想法，那就是，
my god we are at this precipice of
我的天哪，我们正处于危险的边缘，而
danger which we are is because there are
我们确实如此，因为有
nine nuclear armed nations many of which
九个拥有核武器的国家，其中许多国家
are in direct conflict with others or
与其他国家或邻国直接发生冲突，
their neighbors and they are the US,
它们是美国、
Russia, China, the UK, France, India and
俄罗斯、中国、英国、法国、印度和
Pakistan.
巴基斯坦。
Israel, North Korea
以色列、朝鲜，
and there's some threat that Iran
还有伊朗试图采取的某种威胁，
absolutely I mean this is a very very
我的意思是，这绝对是一个非常非常非常
very significant
重大的
threat and you really have to look I
威胁，你真的必须认真对待。我
think the book I stay away from the sort
认为这本书避免了地缘
of geopolitical
政治
posturing or analysis or even um you
姿态、分析，甚至避免了
know opinion about the political aspect
对所有这些政治方面的观点等等
ect of all of this, but I think readers
，但我认为读者
get to take their away their and have
可以从中得出他们自己的结论，
because I have read a lot of the
因为自从一个月前这本书出版以来，我阅读了很多
responses and had a lot of really
评论，也进行了很多非常
interesting conversations since the book
有趣的讨论
published a month ago. But yes, you can
。 但是，你可以
take away what you think about the fact
想想，
what my god you put a tenth nuclear
我的天哪，你们竟然把伊朗这个拥有核武器的国家列入了第十个核武器
armed nation in here that is Iran.
国家。
more destabilizing is that going to be
这将对
to safety and security?
安全保障造成多大的破坏？
And when I look at the list of countries
当我查看
um you've written about that have these
你提到的拥有
nuclear weapons, the US, Russia, they're
核武器的国家名单时，我发现美国和俄罗斯
both basically in proxy wars at the
目前基本上都处于代理人战争之中，
moment with obviously the the war going
显然乌克兰战争仍在
on in Ukraine. Think about Pakistan and
进行。 想想巴基斯坦和
India. Um, Israel and Iran, you know,
印度。 嗯，你知道，以色列和伊朗
drones at each other at the moment. Um,
目前正处于冲突之中，互相发射导弹和无人机。 嗯，
the UK and and France are obviously part
英国和法国显然都是
of NATO. So, they're kind of sucked into
北约成员国。 所以，他们有点被卷入了
the whole Russia, Ukraine, US conflict
俄罗斯、乌克兰和美国之间的冲突，也
that's going on, that proxy war there.
就是那场代理人战争中。
I think the majority of them are
我认为，目前这些国家中的许多国家，甚至绝大多数国家，都
involved in a direct war or some form of
卷入了直接战争或某种形式的
proxy war as it is. And with many of
代理人战争。 而且，很多
these wars, it's hard to find the way
战争都很难找到
that it ends, the way out, the kind of
结束的方式、出路，或者说找到一座通往
golden bridge, because Ukraine aren't
和平的桥梁，因为乌克兰是不会
going to relent. So, Russia aren't going
让步的。 所以，俄罗斯不一定会有
decide one day that they're going to
一天突然决定
lose the war. That would cause
输掉这场战争。 这将对
significant ramifications for Putin, his
普京、他的
reputation, and Russia as a whole. The
声誉以及整个俄罗斯造成重大影响。
US can't let Ukraine lose for a variety
出于各种地缘政治原因，美国不能让乌克兰战败
of geopolitical reasons. And then at the
。
same time, all of this conflict started
与此同时，所有这些冲突都始于
in Israel following the the attack in
以色列遭受袭击之后
Israel, which has sucked Iran in in much
，并将伊朗卷入了
of that region. And it all seems like,
该地区的大部分冲突之中。 这一切似乎都表明，
you know, these are the countries right
这些国家
now that are involved in
目前正卷入一场
the conflict that is scaring many much
冲突，这场冲突在
much many of us um in a significant way.
很大程度上吓坏了我们很多人。
And if all these countries operate in a
如果所有这些国家都以
similar way where there's one individual
类似的方式运作，由一个人
that can make the decision to release
决定是否释放
those weapons,
这些武器，
it is quite scary. The UN Secretary
那就非常可怕了。 联合国秘书长
General said recently that we are one
最近表示，我们距离核世界末日只有一次
misunderstanding,
误解、
one miscalculation
一次误判的距离
away from nuclear Armageddon.
。
And so the scary part of it is that when
所以，可怕的是，当
you look at that sort of verbiage,
你看到这类措辞时，
right, when I talk about, you know,
比如我谈到
nuclear Armageddon, nuclear apocalypse,
核末日、核灾难、
nuclear holocaust,
核浩劫时，
those are words out of the mouths of
这些话竟然出自
some of these leaders. So there is a
某些领导人之口。 因此，人们
very clear notion that if nuclear war
普遍认为，如果核战争
starts, it ends civilization. that is
爆发，文明就会终结。 这一点
almost certainly known among the
在领导层中几乎肯定是众所周知的
leaders. And yet
。 然而，像
Russia and the president of the United
俄罗斯总统、美国总统
States and the leader of North Korea
和朝鲜领导人这样的人却在互相
throwing around threats and terms. You
威胁、抛出各种条件。 你
know, the leader of North Korea recently
知道吗，朝鲜领导人最近
accused the United States of having a
指责美国怀有
sinister intention of provoking nuclear
挑起核战争的险恶用心
war. I mean, that is a provocation. on
。 我的意思是，这是一种挑衅。
top of a provocation, you know, embedded
你知道，这其中还掺杂着挑衅
in. But to your point, what's the point
。但正如你所说，
of being scared? Well, the point is
害怕又有什么用呢？ 关键是
to realize that passivity is not
要认识到，被动应对未必是解决问题的办法
necessarily the answer. That your
。 你对
knowledge of this situation leads to
这种情况的了解会促成
change. That's just the that's just the
改变。 这就是
history of of civilization. One of the
文明史。 这件事
things it did make me think when I
让我思考的一件事是，在
in the United States where we are now
我们现在所在的美国，只有一个人
who can make that decision and that
可以做出这样的决定，而且
there's basically like someone following
基本上就像有人提着一个
the president with a briefcase called
公文包跟着总统，就像
the it's like the football or something.
足球一样。   是的
Yes.
。
What is that football for people that
对于不了解的人来说，足球是什么
don't know?
？   是的
Yeah. And so so now that people know
。 所以现在人们了解了
about the football or they read it,
足球，或者读到了足球相关的内容，
you'll you'll see you can see in
你会发现，在
photographs of the president you will
总统的照片中，
almost if he's in frame you'll see the
几乎只要他在画面中，你都会看到
mill aid. That's the military aid. an
米尔援助。 那是军事援助。 一名
individual who is assigned to be with
被指派
the president 247 365 and inside the
24/7 365 全天候陪伴总统的人员，以及位于五角大楼内部的
football it's called the emergency
紧急
satchel
行李包，里面装着
are two important things there's in
两件重要的物品：一套
instrumentation that allows the
仪器，可以让
president to the national military
国家军事
command center which is the nuclear
指挥中心（即
bunker beneath the Pentagon okay so it's
五角大楼下方的核掩体）识别总统身份；一套
a it's a call and response authent
呼应式身份
authentication
验证系统；
And then there is something called
以及一套俗称“
colloially the black book.
黑皮书”的东西。   有人
And it was told to me the reason it's
告诉我，这
called the black book is because it
本书之所以被称为“黑皮书”，是因为它
involves so much death. And what the
涉及太多死亡事件。 而那本
black book is is a list of nuclear
黑皮书实际上是一份核
strike options for the president to
打击选项清单，供总统
choose from. And so once the president
选择。 因此，一旦总统
is notified that a ballistic missile is
接到弹道导弹正向
coming at the United States and he has
美国袭来的通知，并且他必须决定
to make a decision about a
是否进行
counterattack,
反击，
he must look quickly because as you
他就必须迅速做出决定，因为正如你
learn in the book and as I learned from
在书中了解到的，也正如我从
presidents uh there is a sixinute window
总统们那里了解到的，决策窗口只有60分钟，
and so there's no time for a roundt
所以没有时间进行全面的
discussion.
讨论。   已经
for the president to choose from. And I
为总统准备好了一份选项清单，供其选择。 我
interviewed for the book someone who
为这本书采访了一位
those decisions in the 80s. And he
在 80 年代实际负责其中一些决策的人。 他
described to me in appalling detail what
向我详细描述了在
the Pentagon, like worked out
五角大楼参与这项工作的感受，比如计算出
numerically different targets and why
不同的目标数量，以及为什么
they would be targets in said strike XYZ
这些目标会成为
or Q against said nation. and then later
针对该国的 XYZ 或 Q 打击的目标。 后来，他
seeing the black book and realizing the
看到了那本黑皮书，意识到
like sort of transmutation of that
其中的
information to what was described by the
信息发生了某种转变，正如
only mill aid who's ever gone on the
唯一一位
record speaking about this as
公开谈论过此事的工厂工人所描述的那样，
essentially like a Denny's menu list of
基本上就像丹尼餐厅的
options.
菜单选项列表。
so you understand that this list is so
所以你应该明白，这份清单已经被
watered down into strike options and
简化成了各种打击选项，而且
there is so little time that the
时间非常紧迫，以至于
president in essence has really no idea
总统实际上根本不知道
what he's striking and how many millions
他要打击什么，也不知道
of people will be killed.
会有多少人丧生。
When I hear that, it makes me realize
听到这些，我才意识到
how important the decision to pick our
选择
leaders is. Something I didn't realize
领导人是多么重要。 这是我之前没意识到的
before.
。
Nothing could be more important. And yet
没有什么比这更重要了。 然而，
I learned in the book, and I'm talking
我在书中了解到，而且我指的是
about from former secretaries of
来自前
defense, people very close to the
国防部长、与总统关系非常密切的人的谈话
president, that most presidents are
，大多数总统
illinformed about their role as
对自己
commander-in-chief in a nuclear war.
在核战争中作为三军统帅的角色缺乏了解。
Because, and it was said to me, most
因为，正如有人告诉我的，大多数人都
don't want to know. And again, so this
不想知道。 所以，这
brings us back to that paradox of
又让我们回到了威慑的悖论
deterrence. The original question I
。 我
asked in writing and reporting this
在撰写和报道
book, what if deterrence fails?
本书时提出的最初问题是：如果威慑失败了怎么办？
Deterrence is this idea. We will have so
威慑就是这种理念。 我们将有
many nuclear weapons pointed at the
大量核武器指向
other side. They will have so many
对方。 他们会用很多
nuclear weapons pointed at us. No one
核武器瞄准我们。 没人
would be insane enough to let any of
会傻到放
them loose. That's how we all stay safe.
他们走。 这样我们才能保证安全。
Another way of saying deterrence is more
换句话说，威慑作用在于：更多的
nuclear weapons make us more safe. You
核武器会让我们更安全。 你
can decide if you think that's a little
可以自行判断这是否有点像
Orwellian, but that is what exists.
奥威尔式的，但这就是现实。
Okay. So with that in mind, we should
好的。 所以考虑到这一点，我们
really be doing mental checks on our
真的应该每三个月对我们的领导人进行一次心理健康检查，
leaders every 3 months because we've all
因为我们
probably had an experience with someone
可能都遇到过
episode,
情绪失控的人，
you know, and I'll I'll leave it at
你知道，我就说到这里吧，
episode because there's a variety of
因为
different types of episodes one can
情绪失控有很多不同的类型
have. And I was thinking, well, if the
。 我当时在想，如果
president just has a bit of an episode
总统突然发病，
and gets a little bit paranoid or, you
变得有点妄想，或者，你
know, sort of has a little bit of a
知道，有点像
schizophrenic paranoia,
精神分裂症式的妄想，
which can happen to people for a variety
这种情况可能由于各种
of different unpredictable reasons, then
不可预测的原因发生在人们身上，那么
that president could potentially make a
这位总统就有可能做出
decision to end the planet. And there
毁灭地球的决定。 似乎没有任何
defense mechanism to stop him doing that
防御机制可以阻止他
or her doing that.
或她这样做。
You're reminding me of a famous story
你让我想起了
when Nixon was president, and it was
尼克松担任总统时的一个著名故事，当时正值
during the Watergate scandal. He
水门事件丑闻期间。 他
probably knew the end of his presidency
可能知道自己的总统任期即将结束，
was near and he was very drunk one night
一天晚上他喝得酩酊大醉，
and he began to threaten or rather he
开始威胁，或者更确切地说，他
just began to talk you know in in this
只是开始用那种
sort of extremely verbose drunken manner
极其冗长的醉酒方式说话，
about how he could end the world or kill
说他可以一键毁灭世界或杀死
tens of millions of people with a push
数千万人
of a button. And his it is said that
。 据说，
that Kissinger called up the military
基辛格曾打电话给军方，
and said if the president orders any
说如果总统下令进行任何
kind of a nuclear strike talk to me
形式的核打击，请先跟我谈谈
first. really
。 真的吗？
and do you so do you think that would
你觉得会
have happened?
发生那种事吗？
I mean we you know
我的意思是，你知道，这
it's hard to know isn't it?
很难知道，对吧？
All of these stories unless they come
除非这些故事
out of the mouth of the individual who
出自当事人之口，否则它们本质上都只是
stories. So there's an element of truth
故事。 所以它们肯定包含一些事实成分
to them for sure. Um you know the actual
。 嗯，你知道，真正
command and control who's going to
掌握指挥权的是谁会
follow the rules. People ask me that
遵守规则。 人们经常问我这个
question often and I took that exact
问题，而我对这个问题的理解是，
question like you know I think people
你知道，我认为人们
have a naive that if you're in the
天真地认为，如果你身处
nuclear command and control whether
核指挥控制中心，无论是
you're a missile in a an underground
地下
silo or a submariner on a sub that you
发射井里的导弹还是潜艇上的潜艇兵，
might when you get this command suddenly
当你接到指挥权时，你可能会突然像
Hollywood movie have this moment where
好莱坞电影里那样，突然萌生出
you say my goodness I'm going to save
拯救
the planet rather than destroy it. I put
地球而不是毁灭地球的念头。 我
that question to Dr. Glenn McDuff, the
向洛斯阿拉莫斯国家博物馆的历史学家格伦·麦克杜夫博士提出了这个问题
Los Alamos, the one you and I can't go
，那是一个你我都无法
see. Um, and I said, "Do you think that
参观的秘密博物馆。 嗯，我说：“你认为这种情况
could happen?" And he said, "Annie, you
会发生吗？” 他说：“安妮，你中
Powerball
强力球彩票的几率
than betting on someone in the nuclear
都比赌核武器
chain of command and control to defy
指挥控制系统中的某个人会违抗
orders." And I said, "Why?" and he said,
命令的几率高。” 我问：“为什么？” 他说：
"Well, you are trained to follow
“嗯，你们受过训练，要服从
orders."
命令。”
I spoke to a CIA agent or should I say a
我和一位名叫安德鲁·布斯塔曼特的中央情报局特工，或者应该说是一位
former CIA agent called Andrew
前中央情报局特工交谈过
Bustamante. Might have seen him. He does
。 可能见过他。 他做
some podcasts. And um after speaking to
一些播客节目。 嗯，和他谈过之后
him, I I completely agree because as he
，我完全同意，因为正如他
said, he was trained to basically he was
所说，他接受的训练基本上就是让
he would follow orders in that moment.
他在那一刻服从命令。
and they even do drills to make sure
他们甚至还会进行
dummy drills to make sure that they're
模拟演练，以确保他们在
prepared, I guess, psychologically to
心理上做好准备，能够
follow through on those instructions. It
执行这些指令。 这
made me think as well that if if um what
让我想到，如果……如果
if the president's dead, what if the
总统去世了怎么办？如果
president is hit by a nuclear weapon
总统被
from another country and now they can no
其他国家的核武器击中，他们就无法
longer make the decision? Is the
再做出决定了怎么办？ 是否将
decision deferred on to somebody else?
决定权交给其他人？
Well, I take the reader through that
我之所以向读者详细介绍这些内容，正是
precisely because those are the kind of
因为
sources as I was reporting this. On the
我在报道此事时必须向我的消息来源提出这类问题。
one hand, as I was learning what happens
一方面，当我了解到
after a launch is detected, because we
发射被探测到后的几秒和几分钟内会发生什么时，因为我们
have a satellite system that detects the
有一个卫星系统可以
launch of a nuclear weapon in under a
在不到一秒的时间内探测到核武器的发射
fraction of a second,
，
but it's not always very trustworthy.
但它并不总是非常可靠。
This is why I'm concerned.
这就是我担忧的原因。
The ours is very trustworthy as far as I
据我了解，ours 非常值得信赖
understand. It's called CBERS. It's
。 它叫做 CBERS。 它
built by Lockheed and it's astonishingly
由洛克希德公司制造，性能极其
powerful. Other nations do not have that
强大。 其他国家没有
same kind of technology
同样的技术，
because I was reading about the sort of
因为我读到过
historic um mistakes that were made.
历史上犯下的那些错误。
Sometimes people thought there was a a
有时人们以为有
nuclear bomb or a strike coming and it
核弹或袭击要来了，结果发现
was actually just a bunch of swans.
只是一群天鹅。
Absolutely.
绝对地。
I was a little bit like
我当时有点想，
I mean these are these are you know this
我的意思是，你知道，这距离
misunderstanding away from nuclear
核
Armageddon.
世界末日只有一步之遥，一次误判，一次误解。
What are those instances from history
历史上有哪些案例中，
where the nuclear detection system was
核探测系统被
triggered and someone in some country
触发，但某个国家的某个人却
decided um not to follow through on a
决定不执行
notification. I think the most
通知？ 我认为
interesting stories that I report come
我报道的最有趣的故事都来自
firshand witness to it because what
亲历者，因为
often happens is the telephone game, you
经常发生的是传话游戏，你
know, whereby one person tells the story
知道，就是一个人讲述故事，
and then your imagin you add a detail.
然后你的想象力会添加一些细节。
So I write about a couple of them in the
我在书中写到了其中几个人
book, but one of them came to me
，但其中一个是我亲身经历的，
firsthand and I'll share that with you
我会和你们分享，他
which was former Secretary of Defense
就是前国防部长
Bill Perry and he was on the night watch
比尔·佩里，他在
during the Carter administration. He
卡特政府时期负责夜间值班。 他当时
wasn't the secretary of defense yet. He
还不是国防部长。 在那之前
had like the job before that, the
，他曾担任
the Pentagon. But it was his his night
五角大楼的研究与工程主管。 但正是他的夜间
watch informed the president job. And he
值班经历让他了解了总统的工作。
was told by the National Military
国家军事
Command Center, which is the bunker
指挥中心（位于五角大楼下方的掩体）告诉他，有
the way from Soviet Russia.
来自苏联的弹道导弹正在运送过来。
Nebraska, the Stratcom bunker. And not
内布拉斯加州奥菲特空军基地下方的核掩体——战略司令部掩体——证实了这一点。 而且，
only were they intercontinental
它们不仅是
ballistic missiles flying at the United
射向美国的洲际弹道导弹
States, but they were sublaunched
，而且是
ballistic missiles coming at the United
射向美国的潜射弹道导弹
States. And it was a massive motherload
。 而且那是一大批
of warheads. And Perry described to me,
核弹头。 正如我在书中记述的那样，佩里向我描述了当时的感受，你
to try and process in your mind, oh my
试图在脑海中处理这件事，哦，我的
god, I'm going to have to tell the
天哪，我必须告诉总统，
and going to have to and he is going to
而且他必须
have to make a counterattack.
做出反击。
And within a matter of minutes, he got
几分钟之内，他就
word that it was a mistake. And a
得知这是一个错误。
mistake, you might ask, like a mistake?
你可能会问，那像错误一样的错误呢？
How does a mistake happen? What he told
错误是如何发生的？ 他告诉
me was that it was a VHS tape, a
我，那是一盘 VHS 录像带，是一场
simulated war game, a simulated attack
模拟战争游戏，模拟
by the Soviet Union against the United
苏联对
States. And the VHS tape had mistakenly
美国的攻击。 那盘 VHS 录像带被误
been inserted into a machine in the
放进了
nuclear bunker beneath the Pentagon. And
五角大楼下方核掩体里的一台机器里。
because it is linked to Stratcom, it was
因为它与战略传播有关，所以
seen in both places.
在这两个地方都能看到它。
And Perry said to me, "It looked real
佩里对我说：“它看起来很逼真，
because it was meant to look real."
因为它本来就是要看起来很逼真。”
There was a president you talk about
你提到的那位总统曾
that played a nuclear war game and
进行过核战争演习，结果
discovered that there could be no
发现战争中没有
winners.
赢家。
So, Proud Prophet
所以，《骄傲的先知》
is one of the few
是
a very rare declassified nuclear war
极少数已解密的核战争
game. People talk about, you know,
游戏之一。 人们常说，
jealously guarded secrets in the United
美国政府里有许多严加保密的秘密
States government. You can be sure that
。 可以肯定的是，
anything having to do with nuclear war
任何与核战争
gaming is way up there in the top
游戏有关的事情，
secrets along with what is actually in
以及
that black book. But the proud profit
那本黑皮书里的内容，都属于最高机密。 但那场令人骄傲的利润
war game was declassified. Reagan had
战争游戏被解密了。 是里根
ordered it. I don't believe he
下令的。 我不认为他
participated in it. His sect desk,
参与其中。 他的部门，以及
everybody in the command nuclear command
核指挥控制中心的所有人，
in 1983.
在1983年参与了为期两周的演习。
And this is declassified. I reprint some
而这已经解密了。 我在书中重印了其中的一些内容
of it in the book. And if you have a
。 如果你仔细
look at it, you might say to yourself,
看看，你可能会想，
well, what's the point of declassifying
好吧，解密这样的东西有什么意义呢
something that looks like this? It's
？ 它
just black. It's like there's a number
通体漆黑。 就像这里有个数字，
here and a word there and a page number.
那里有个单词，还有页码。
But mostly it's entirely redacted. And
但大部分内容都被完全涂黑了。
so what's the point of declassifying it?
那么，解密它的意义何在呢？
Well, for the public, something very
对于公众而言，
valuable came out of that, which is it
这件事带来了非常有价值的东西，那就是它
allowed a certain civilian who was
让一位参与其中的平民——
participating, a Yale professor named
耶鲁大学教授
Paul Bracken, to actually speak about it
保罗·布雷肯——得以公开谈论此事
in a general way. He couldn't, you know,
。 你知道，他
couldn't tell OPsac, but he could
不能告诉 OPsac，但他
generally talk about it. And what he
通常可以谈论这件事。 他
said in his own book was that no matter
在自己的书中写道，无论
how nuclear war begins, NATO's involved,
核战争如何爆发，北约都会卷入，
NATO is not involved. China's involved,
北约也不会卷入。 中国参与其中，
China's no matter how it begins, it ends
无论事情如何开始，最终都会演变成
in nuclear Armageddon. And Bracken's
核战争。 布雷肯
words was that everyone left really
说，每个人离开时都非常
depressed.
沮丧。
Nuclear Armageddon essentially means the
核末日本质上意味着
world is destroyed.
世界毁灭。
Nuclear Armageddon is the world is
核末日是指世界
destroyed. And when you get to the end
毁灭。 当你读到
of the book, which happens in 72
这本书的结尾时，你会发现，这发生在 72
minutes, and that comes from something
分钟之内。这源于
that former Stratcom director, General
前战略司令部主任
Keeler, said to me when we were
基勒将军在与我
discussing and interviewing, and I said
讨论和采访时对我说的话，当时我
we I asked him about what could happen
问他，
if there was a nuclear exchange between
如果
Russia and the United States. And he
俄罗斯和美国之间发生核战争会发生什么。 他
said the world could end in the next
说，世界可能在接下来的
couple of hours.
几个小时内毁灭。
So from where we are now in this
所以，从我们现在的
conversation to the end of this
谈话到
conversation, if a nuclear war broke out
谈话结束，如果爆发核战争，
and we were sat here, by the end of this
而我们当时正坐在这里，那么到
conversation,
谈话结束时，
basically the entire world will be
基本上整个世界都会被
destroyed.
毁灭。   在
the first missile hit. That was shocking
第一枚导弹击中目标之前，你我甚至都不会知道。 令我震惊的是，
by uh Obama's FEMA director. So FEMA,
奥巴马时期的联邦紧急事务管理署署长竟然证实了这一点。 所以，FEMA，即
the Federal Emergency Management Agency,
联邦紧急事务管理局，
is the is the agency in the United
是
States that's in charge of disasters,
美国负责应对灾害的机构，
right? So if there's a hurricane or a
对吧？ 所以，如果发生飓风、
flood or an earthquake, FEMA steps in to
洪水或地震，联邦紧急事务管理局（FEMA）就会介入
help the people. They have something
帮助民众。 他们有一种
called population protection planning.
叫做人口保护规划的东西。
Craig Fugate was Obama's FEMA director
克雷格·富盖特曾担任奥巴马时期的联邦紧急事务管理署署长
for 8 years and he just covered an
8 年，他报道了美国发生的
extraordinary amount of catastrophes in
众多灾难
the United States. He was also
。 他还
responsible for planning for a nuclear
负责制定核
war. He told me that they did that. He
战争计划。 他告诉我他们确实这么做了。 他
also said, "We plan for asteroid
还说：“我们制定了应对小行星
strikes." These are called low
撞击的计划。” 这些被称为低
probability high consequence events. But
概率高后果事件。 但
what Fugate told me that was shocking is
富盖特告诉我的那番话让我感到震惊，那就是
planning in a nuclear war because
核战争中没有人口保护计划，因为
everyone will be dead. And he explained
所有人都会死。 他向我解释说，
that he could do as FEMA director. He
作为联邦紧急事务管理署署长，他无能为力。 他
would really be putting his efforts from
会在
which is called Mount Weather. he would
名为“气象山”的核掩体中全力以赴。 他将致力于
of government issues, the continuity of
政府的连续性问题，
like the government has what are called
比如政府的连续性，即政府拥有所谓的
essential functions. So an you know as a
基本职能。 所以，你知道，当
nuclear war is happening the government
核战争爆发时，政府却
is trying to prepare to keep the
试图维持
government running which is a form of
运转，这
fantasy in itself and when you read
本身就是一种幻想。当你读到
Fugate's interviews with me he's just so
富盖特对我的采访时，他非常
candid about how there is nothing anyone
坦率地告诉我，没有人
can do and you know what he told me was
能做任何事。你知道，他告诉我的话让我
so shocking I went back to him and said
非常震惊，所以我回去问他，
like I just want to really make sure
我想确认一下
these are your actual quotes that you
这些话是否真的是你说的。他
that that and he absolutely you know he
确实说过，而且他
was one of the first people to write an
是这本书在美国出版后最早在亚马逊上写书评的人之一。
I find that both terrifying but also
我发现这既令人恐惧又
heartening for this reason is that a lot
令人鼓舞，原因在于，很多
of these people who leave office because
卸任的人——
my sources are all former and then the
我的消息来源都是前任——以及他们在
title they when they are in the command
指挥
and control. They are very focused on
控制部门时的头衔。 他们非常专注于
doing their job. Hence what we spoke
做好自己的工作。 这就是为什么我们
about earlier about like following
之前谈到要服从
orders. They are civil servants. They
命令的原因。 他们是公务员。 他们
are dedicated civil servants. They
是尽职尽责的公务员。 他们
believe in national security. They
相信国家安全。 他们
believe in, you know, the perseverance
相信
of government. And then they leave
政府的坚持不懈。 然后他们卸任，又变回了
office and they are just regular people
普通人
again. And that's when the heart I think
。 我认为，正是在这个时候，内心
begins to lead. And particularly as
开始主导一切。 尤其是随着
people get older because I interview a
人们年龄的增长，因为我采访了
lot of people in their 80s and 90s and
很多八九十岁的人，
then they begin to think about what this
他们开始思考这
means in terms of legacy.
对于传承意味着什么。
What is nuclear command and control
核指挥与控制究竟是什么？即使表面上看起来严密
really as buttoned up as this is might
无懈可击，他们也可能只是在
be them talking you know as as I
谈论它，就像我之前
thought?
想的那样？   在当今
so rapidly changing both geopolitically
地缘政治
and also in terms of technology?
和技术都日新月异的世界里，这真的是个好主意吗？
comes to mind when I ask who the most
当我问你，在你认识的
troubled person was in terms of the work
人当中，谁是工作中遇到的最令人困扰的人，
they participated in or troubled in the
或者谁是因其
what they know and what it means for
所知、对
humanity and how they're grappling with
人类的意义以及他们如何应对这些问题而感到最困扰的人时，你脑海中会浮现出哪个人？
that. the most concerned and sort of the
最关心此事、
most activated by all means would be
最积极行动的人当属
former Secretary of Defense Bill Perry.
前国防部长比尔·佩里。
And he's now in his 90s and I I don't
他现在已经90多岁了，而且我
believe he's doing interviews anymore.
相信他不再接受采访了。
But it it's not surprising that Perry
但佩里向
shared with me his intense worry about
我表达了他对这一切的强烈担忧，这并不奇怪，
all of this because he has been actively
因为他一直在积极地致力于
working on this and you know for at
此，你知道，
least 15 20 years and when I say this I
至少有 15 到 20 年的时间了，我这么说的
mean bringing the information to the
意思是把这些信息带给
public so that the public is aware. He
公众，让公众了解。 他
wrote his own book with a colleague
和一位名叫“按钮”的同事合著了一本书
called The Button. And he has, you know,
。 而且，你知道，
really he did a podcast called At the
他确实做过一个叫做《濒临崩溃边缘》的播客
Brink. And what's fascinating is Perry
。 而最令人着迷的是，佩里
spent most of his life dedicated to what
一生的大部分时间都致力于
you might call the military-industrial
所谓的军工
complex, right? to the research and
复合体，对吧？ 这与
development of weapon systems that I
我在
write about in my other books, the DARPA
其他书中，
book in particular, because this is all
特别是关于 DARPA 的书中所描述的武器系统的研究和开发息息相关，因为这与
part and parcel to what we're talking
我们在这里讨论的内容密不可分，即
industry, military, weapon system
军事武器系统
industry that is in a constant state of
行业正处于不断
forward movement. It's deeply tied to
向前发展的状态。 它与
economics, to jobs, to prosperity. And
经济、就业和繁荣息息相关。
so where does that take us? And and at
那么，这会把我们引向何方呢？ 而
what point does it end? It was
这一切何时结束？
Eisenhower who said in his famous speech
艾森豪威尔在他著名的演讲中谈到了
this so-called military-industrial
所谓的军工
complex because Eisenhower spoke of it
复合体，公众正是在这次
in his farewell speech. But he also said
演讲中真正了解了它。 但他
an important thing in the second half of
在那次演讲的后半部分也提到了一个重要的观点，这个观点并
that speech which doesn't get nearly as
没有得到足够的
much airtime which is that a
重视，那就是，要
is how you balance sort of an idea of
平衡
peace with an idea of defense.
和平理念和防御理念，就需要有知识、有警觉的公民。
And I think what frightens both of us
我认为我们俩一
that we talked about in the beginning
开始就讨论过的那个令我们感到恐惧的问题
here was that peace and defense are very
是，和平与防御与
different than constant states of war.
持续不断的战争状态截然不同。
72 minutes. You you go through this in
72分钟。
the book minute almost minute by minute
书中几乎是一分钟一分钟地
showing exactly what will happen. We
详细描述了接下来会发生什么。 我们
know in those first couple of minutes
知道，在最初的几分钟内，
there's a notification that there's a
就会收到通知，说有
you know a nuclear bomb coming in from
一枚核弹正从某个
somewhere. My question on that was and I
地方袭来。 我的问题正是关于这一点的，而且我
was thinking about this earlier as we
之前在
were talking about it. How does the
讨论这个问题的时候也一直在思考这个问题。
president know? How does the world
总统怎么知道的？
leader of that country know, the prime
那个国家的领导人
minister of the UK, whoever it might be
，无论是英国首相、
or Netanyahu or Putin know where that
内塔尼亚胡还是普京，怎么会知道那枚
nuclear bomb has come from? Because we
核弹来自哪里呢？ 因为我们
talked about this sort of black black
谈到了总统藏在助手随身携带的足球里的那本秘密场所
book of places, this menu that the
名录，也就是总统藏在足球里的那份菜单
aid is carrying around.
。
How does he know which place to pick on
他怎么知道该从菜单上的哪家餐厅订购
the menu to send a nuclear bomb back?
一枚核弹送回去呢？   这是一个
Powerful distinction, right? This is not
很重要的区别，对吧？ 这不像
911 where suddenly there are planes in
911事件，突然间
the trade center towers and you know,
世贸中心双塔上出现了飞机，然后
everyone is scrambling to say who did
每个人都争先恐后地猜测是谁干的，
this and the CIA is saying this is
而中央情报局则说是基地
al-Qaeda. It has the mark of but no one
组织干的。 它带有某种印记，但没有人能
knows for sure. This is not that. This
确定。 这不是那样。
is the fact that for 79 years, the
事实是，79年来，
United States has been building nuclear
美国一直在制造
weapons, nuclear weapon systems, and
核武器、核武器系统，以及
also systems to detect other people's
探测其他国家
nuclear weapons should they have them.
是否拥有核武器的系统。
But what if the submarines?
但如果潜艇呢？
Okay, so good point on the submarines,
好的，关于潜艇的观点很有道理，
which is but we have a set of satellites
但是我们还有一组
called sibers, which are parked. Now I'm
叫做西伯利亚的卫星，它们目前处于停泊状态。 现在我
only t when you said what how would
才明白，你说
Netanyahu know how would the president
内塔尼亚胡怎么会知道，总统怎么会知道，
of that is a different scenario.
那又是另一种情况了。
What I am talking about is the US
我指的是美国
president because I have interviewed
总统，因为我采访
people in the US defense department and
过美国国防部和
the intelligence community and the
情报部门的人员，
defense department knows precisely where
国防部可以在武器发射后一秒内精确地知道其来源，
launch because the cber satellites can
因为核导弹卫星可以
measure the hot rocket exhaust. So you
测量火箭的高温尾气。 你
imagine a rocket taking off, lots of
可以想象一枚火箭升空，
fire beneath it. That is measured
下方燃起熊熊烈火。 这是
from 22,000 m up in geoscyn. I mean,
从海拔 22,000 米的高度测量的。 我的意思是，
that is just a technological
这简直是一项令人
astonishment.
惊叹的技术成就。
And then there begins the data sent down
然后，数据开始被发送
to these various commands in the United
到美国的各个指挥部
States, the aerospace data center, the
、航空航天数据中心、
space force, and they begin measuring
太空部队，他们开始测量
the trajectory of the missile and
导弹的轨迹，并
figuring out where it's going to go.
计算出它的落点。
like it's not going to Moscow and it's
就像它既不会去莫斯科，也
not going to Guam. Those would be
不会去关岛一样。 那将是
opposite directions. Is it going to San
相反的方向。 是去
Francisco or is it going to the east
旧金山还是去东
coast? That is learned in 100 seconds
海岸？ 大约100秒就能学会
approximately. Okay. Now, you are right.
。 好的。 没错，你说得对。
You cannot det you if some if a
如果某艘
submarine launches a ballistic missile,
潜艇发射弹道导弹，你无法确定它来自哪里，因为你根本
there's no way of knowing where that
无法知道它来自哪里
came from. Which is why in the scenario
。 这就是为什么在我的设想中，这种情况会
I have that happen and it creates a
发生，并引发
whole other set of problems.
一系列其他问题。
What are those? I I mean I mean what is
那是什么？ 我的意思是，这个
the answer to that? Cuz I was imagining
问题的答案是什么？ 因为我当时在想，
if the cberous system sees a nuclear
如果计算机系统探测到一枚
bomb coming out of the Pacific Ocean. I
核弹从太平洋飞来会怎么样。 我的
mean that could be Rishi Sunnak. That
意思是，那可能是里希·苏纳克。 那
could be that could be the UK firing one
可能是英国
at America. It could be, you know, could
向美国发射的一枚导弹。 你知道，可能
be anybody.
是任何人。
You are absolutely right that there is
您说得完全正确，我们根本
no way of knowing. And in the scenario
无从得知。
that I chose because I wanted to try to
我之所以选择这个场景，是因为我想尝试
take the reader through a logical
带领读者经历一个合乎逻辑的
sequence, if you could even call any of
顺序，如果你还能称之为合乎
this logical because it's all, you know,
逻辑的话，因为这一切都，你知道，
they call it MAD mutual assured
他们称之为相互确保
destruction. It's really madness
摧毁（MAD）。 这真是太疯狂了，
but you cannot know who launched that.
但你无法知道是谁发起的。
Uh
所以，在这种情况下，我们就直接攻击敌人吗？
I mean do you know what I do?
你知道我是做什么的吗？
You have a new task. You are going to
你接到了一项新任务。 你打算把
write nuclear war an even worse
核战争描述成一个更糟糕的
scenario.
场景。
Well because that's what you would do
因为
right if you're President Biden your aid
如果你是拜登总统，你的助手就会
turns to you and goes hi President
对你说：“总统先生，一枚
there's a nuclear bomb heading our way.
核弹正朝我们飞来。”
I go I know who exactly who that who did
我知道是谁干的
that.
。
and you might start firing a couple of
你可能会开始向
back back at just the people that you
你
assume would do it and then they do the
认为会这么做的人发起反击，然后他们也会这样做
same. Um,
。 嗯，
that are owned by Russia and China
俄罗斯和中国拥有的核动力潜艇
regularly come within a couple hundred
经常出现在美国东西
miles of east co of each coast of the
海岸东海岸几百英里的范围内
United States. And you can assume the
。 你可以
same about England. And how do we know
对英格兰的情况作同样的假设。 我们怎么知道
this? Well, you can't see a submarine
这一点呢？ 虽然你无法实时看到潜艇的
moving in real time, but you can track
移动，但事后你可以追踪
the submarine's movements after the
潜艇的动向
fact, owing to a very complex system of
，这得益于我们拥有的非常复杂的
underwater surveillance systems that we
水下监视系统
have in place. And there's a map that
。 在
appeared in a recent Defense Department
最近国防部
budget request to Congress, which I
向国会提交的预算申请中出现了一张地图（我
reproduce in the book, that shows just
在书中也转载了这张地图），它显示了
how close those submarines, those enemy
敌方
submarines get to the coast. And that
潜艇距离海岸有多近。 这样可以将
reduces the travel time of a ballistic
弹道导弹的飞行时间缩短
missile down to under 10 minutes. And so
到 10 分钟以内。 因此，认为
this idea that we really are living at
我们真的生活在
the edge of apocalypse is not an
世界末日的边缘这种说法并非
exaggeration. The question is how would
夸张。 问题是，这一切将如何
this start? Why would this start? Again,
开始？ 这一切是如何开始的？
read the scenario and you begin to
再读一遍场景，你就会开始
realize
意识到
this could start in or have a discussion
这可能始于或
with you and you this could start in so
与你进行讨论，而这可能始于
many the training test tape. I mean, and
许多训练测试录像带中。 我的意思是，
the real takeaway is asking ourselves is
真正的问题在于，我们该扪心自问，
why do none of us know about this or
为什么我们
most of us rather?
大多数人对此一无所知？
There's so many ways this could start
这件事的开端有很多种，其中一种
and one of them one of them obviously
显然在
society since you started writing the
你开始写这本书以来就一直是社会关注的焦点，
book which is artificial intelligence.
那就是人工智能。   不过在此
Before I get to that though I really
之前，我真的
want to I really want to close off on
想，我真的想结束
this 72 minutes. I understand the first
这72分钟的讨论。 开头那几分钟我能听懂
couple of minutes there. Um what does
。 嗯，
the person listening to this need to
听这段话的人需要
know about what happens in the
了解接下来发生的事情吗
subsequence? What are 60 minutes?
？  60分钟是什么？
being determined and we're talking in
确定弹道导弹轨迹的过程非常迅速，我们现在谈论的是整个
the first minutes of the sequence
过程的最初几分钟，
because everyone is getting ready to
因为每个人都在准备向
tell the president because what they're
总统汇报，因为他们
going to tell the president is sir you
要告诉总统的是，先生，您
need to choose a counterattack. That is
需要选择反击策略。 这
called get the blue clock running.
叫做启动蓝色时钟。
Does the president not like get in some
总统难道不想赶紧
plane super quick?
搭飞机吗？
So we'll get there in a second because
所以我们马上就讲到这一点，因为这就是
that's where the that's a decision tree
一个决策树
problem. So everyone is working on
问题。 所以大家都在努力
figuring out the trajectory of the
确定弹道导弹的轨迹，
confirmation when you see it and by the
当你看到它时，就能得到第一个确认。
way a ballistic missile cannot be
顺便说一句，弹道导弹是无法
redirected or recalled cannot be. Now
改变方向或召回的。
ultimately the defense department will
最终，国防部将
wait for second confirmation of that
等待地面雷达系统对该导弹的第二次确认
missile from a ground radar system. We
。 我们在
have them around the world. The one in
世界各地都有它们。
the scenario that would see it is in
设想中会出现这种情况的地点在
Alaska. It has to be able to see and
阿拉斯加。 它必须能够看到并
confirm that missile is definitely
确认导弹确实正朝
coming this way. And that happens at
这个方向飞来。 这种情况大约发生在
around 8 or 9 minutes. And so the
8 或 9 分钟的时候。 因此，
process in between them, everyone's
在他们之间，每个人都在
getting ready to brief the president
准备向总统汇报
about a counterattack. And so in the
反击计划。 因此，在这种
scenario, the president learns around 3
情况下，总统大约 3 分钟后得知消息，
minutes and then they're waiting on the
然后他们就等待
secondary confirmation. And in my
第二轮确认。 在
interviews with the Secret Service, as I
采访特勤局人员并
was reporting the book, interesting
撰写本书的过程中，发生了一些有趣的
things would happen. Exactly like your
事情。 就像你的
question, like wait a minute, what would
问题一样，等等，
would the president be staying at the
总统会住在
White House? So I, as the reporter, put
白宫吗？ 所以，作为记者，我向特勤局
that question to the former director of
前局长提出了这个问题，
the Secret Service who explains to me
他向我解释了有
how there is a team called the counter
一个名为反
assault team. Um, and that that is the
突击队的团队。 嗯，这就是
C of the Secret Service that's going to
特勤局的准军事组织，他们会
always be there to move the president
随时待命，在
really fast if need be. And in this
必要时迅速护送总统。 在这种
situation, they make a decision, we're
情况下，他们做出了决定，我们要
moving him. If the target is Washington
调走他。 如果目标是华盛顿
DC or anywhere on the east east coast
特区，或者美国东海岸的任何地方
for that matter, we cannot have the
，我们就不能让
president anywhere near ground zero. And
总统靠近爆炸中心。
their job that they are sworn to do is
他们宣誓履行的职责是
to protect the president. And so that
保护总统。 这样一来，就会出现
then you're going to have a bit of a
某种
stalemate because the military command
僵局，因为军方指挥部
wants the president on on comms to be
希望总统能够通过通讯向
able to give him counterstrike orders.
他下达反击命令。
that is what they want and they can only
这就是他们想要的，而他们只能
get those orders from the president. But
从总统那里得到这些命令。 但
the Secret Service has a totally
特勤局却有着完全
different agenda. And in my scenario,
不同的目的。 在我的设想中，
the Secret Service, considering they're
考虑到
the only ones in the room that are
房间里只有特勤局人员携带
armed, win. They take the president out
武器，所以特勤局获胜。 他们把总统带走，
and he flies out of Washington DC in
他乘坐海军陆战队一号飞机离开华盛顿特区
Marine One.
。
Marine One being the helicopter.
海军陆战队一号指的是直升机。   就是那架
The helicopter that is that Yeah. You
直升机。是的。 你
know, and then I learned even more
知道，然后我了解到更多
interesting details like, okay, so in
有趣的细节，比如，好吧，在这种
the scenario, the likely situation is
情况下，很可能的情况是
that the electromagnetic pulse will
电磁脉冲会
really threaten the the electronic
严重威胁
system in Marine 1 and it will be in
Marine 1 的电子系统，使其面临
deep danger of crashing.
崩溃的严重危险。
What is that for people that don't know?
对于不了解的人来说，那是什么意思？
For people that don't know, an an
对于不了解的人来说，
electromagnetic pulse is like a three
电磁脉冲就像一种三
pulsed sort of shock wave that
脉冲冲击波，它
essentially just zeros out electronics.
本质上就是使电子设备归零。
Imagine your house getting struck by
想象一下你的房子被
lightning. a direct hit and no surge
闪电击中。 直接撞击，且没有浪涌
suppressor. I mean, it's just it's all
抑制器。 我的意思是，所有
the electronics go out and that will
电子设备都会停止工作，这种情况
almost certainly happen. Marine One is
几乎肯定会发生。 海军陆战队一号直升机经过
outfitted, retrofitted against EMP
改装，可以抵御电磁脉冲
attack because they think about these
攻击，因为他们考虑到了这些
things, but no one knows if it's going
情况，但没有人知道这是否
to really work. It's been tested in a
真的有效。 它已经在密闭舱中测试过了
chamber.
。
So, so what you're saying, sorry, just
所以，抱歉，我再
to be clear, is that whoever's attacking
确认一下，你的意思是，无论谁攻击
the United States or another country
美国或其他国家，
would send an electronic pulse first.
都会先发出电子脉冲。
No, the pulse is part of the of the
不，脉冲是
bomb. Okay?
炸弹的一部分。 好的？
It's it's a it's inherent in the nuclear
这是
explosion. Okay?
核爆炸固有的特性。 好的？
And so even if even if you're getting
所以，即使你把
the president out, if he's 7 8 9 miles
总统救了出来，即使他
10 miles out of ground zero, as they
距离世贸中心遗址有 7、8、9 或 10 英里，当他们
rush, because remember this is all
争分夺秒地把他从白宫救出来时，因为记住这一切都
happening in 30 minutes, under 30
发生在 30 分钟之内，甚至不到 30
minutes, as they rush to get him out of
分钟，
the White House, the EMP could seriously
电磁脉冲可能会严重
damage the Marine One. So, the Secret
损坏海军陆战队一号。 因此，
Service people I interviewed explained
我采访的特勤局人员
to me that they would have a backup
向我解释说，他们会有一个备用
plan, which would be to tandem jump the
方案，那就是让
president out of the aircraft in a with
总统和另一名
with a parachute. They would strap the
特勤局人员一起跳伞离开飞机。 他们会把
president onto them and jump out of the
总统绑在自己身上，然后跳出
aircraft because at least there would be
飞机，因为至少这样
the the aircraft is going to crash if it
飞机就不会因为受到
gets hit by the electromagnetic pulse.
电磁脉冲的冲击而坠毁。
So, at least there's a better chance.
所以，至少机会更大了。
Well, then you have to have the mill aid
那么，你必须让那个幕后黑手带个
has to have a parachute cuz he's got the
降落伞，因为他掌握着
black book and the dire the the special
黑皮书，而且
agent in charge of the president is
总统的特工负责人
definitely going to go. So then I
肯定会被干掉。 后来我才
learned that this incredible detail that
知道，
there aren't parachutes in Marine 1. So
海军陆战队一号飞机上竟然没有降落伞。所以
they have to go to the White House
他们必须去白宫
office to get the parachutes. You know,
办公室领取降落伞。 你知道，
these kind of details, I believe,
我相信，这些细节
provide the reader with a number of
能让读者对很多
things like the the astonishing
事情有惊人的
understanding of how many different
理解，比如，有多少不同的
scenarios are in play all the time, you
场景一直在上演，你
know, being rehearsed so that we because
知道，这些场景一直在演练，以至于
we might have a nuclear war at the same
我们可能会爆发核战争，而与此同时，我们
time that the messaging is we will never
传递的信息却是我们永远不会爆发
have a nuclear war. And then when you
核战争。 当你
begin to look at all the competing
开始审视所有可能
agendas that will happen, you you
出现的相互竞争的议程时，你就会
realize it's just chaos upon mayhem.
意识到，这简直就是一团糟。
What if the president dies in the strike
如果总统在袭击中丧生，
and before we've made a counterattack
而我们还没来得及进行反击怎么办？
which is something that Stratcom thinks
战略司令部
about and it's certainly why I have that
考虑过这个问题，这也是我把这种情况纳入
in the scenario because if the president
方案的原因，因为如果总统
is the only one that can order a count a
是唯一可以下令进行能够
counterattack that can launch nuclear
发射核武器的反击的人
weapons, what if he dies? And so I
，如果他死了怎么办？ 因此，我
learned in the reporting that if you're
在报道中了解到，如果你是
the president, let's say he even gives
总统，假设他下达了
the order, okay, here's my counter
命令，那么，好吧，这是我的
strike. I'm choosing this from the black
反击。 我从黑皮书中选了这个
book.
。
The situ the command and control is set
指挥控制系统的
up that if the president orders 82
设置是，如果总统下令发射 82 枚
nuclear weapons in response,
核武器作为回应，
you can't launch 83 nuclear weapons.
你不可能发射 83 枚核武器。   只有
It's 82 and 82 only. And then to do
82和82。 然后，
another launch requires passwords. I
再次启动系统就需要密码。 我的
mean, it requires so much bureaucracy.
意思是，这需要太多的官僚程序。
There's not time for that. And so,
没时间做那件事了。 因此，在
little detail inside of the nuclear
核
command and control apparatus called a
指挥和控制装置中有一个几乎不为人知的小细节，叫做
universal unlock code, which I learned
通用解锁码，这是我
about in the book. And the eyebrow goes
在书中了解到的。
up for exactly that reason, as did mine
正因如此，我的眉毛才被挑了起来，就像我当时那样。
when I Wait, what? And then you find out
等等，什么？ 然后你发现
that the president can release to the
总统可以向
stratcom commander
战略司令部司令发布
the universal unlock code which
通用解锁码，其内容
basically says, "Okay, you if I die, you
基本上是：“好吧，如果我死了，你
have permission to launch
可以发射第
nuclear weapon number 83 or nuclear
83 号核武器或第
weapon number 5,000, you know, all the
5000 号核武器，你知道，一直到
way up." And that
最高级别。” 这
is a pretty shocking concept.
真是一个令人震惊的想法。
the president responds to the nuclear
总统对核
attack,
攻击做出回应，
hits, I don't know, let's say they they
打击，我不知道，假设他们
hit Russia, they send the submarines out
打击俄罗斯，他们派出潜艇
to send the um ICBUM or whatever it's
发射……或者不
called to hit strike Russia. Russia have
管它叫什么，去打击俄罗斯。 俄罗斯
these submarines as well. They send more
也有这些潜艇。 他们寄回的更多
back.
。
nuclear, you know, that 72 that 72nd
核灾难的后果是什么？你知道，就是那72分钟……那72
minute? because I imagine from the
分钟？ 因为我设想，从
minute the president hears that um gets
总统听到消息的那一刻起，也就是收到
been confirmed it's had the second
确认消息的通知，或者说第二次
confirmation he's going to make the
确认消息后，他就会决定
decision to fire nuclear weapons back I
发射核武器进行反击。
assume and then I mean from there it's
然后，我的意思是，从那时起，就全是
from a sub and hits a nuclear power
核打击了。在我看来，有一种叫做“干扰总统”的概念，意思是让总统在我描述的情景中得知，朝鲜发射了一枚弹道导弹，然后第二枚导弹又从潜艇上射来，击中了
plant in California. Why did you pick
加利福尼亚州的一座核电站。 你为什么选择
North Korea?
朝鲜？
I picked North Korea because of my
我选择朝鲜是因为我
interviews with Richard Garwin, the
采访了理查德·加文，他是
designer of the nuclear thermonuclear
核热核
bomb, the first one which you designed
炸弹的设计者，也是你
for Teller.
为泰勒设计的第一枚核弹。
Because in our interviews, I asked him
因为在采访中，我问过他
what scared me most. Garwin also in his
我最害怕的是什么。 加文现年已超过
90s has advised every president of the
90 岁，
United States since Eisenhower. He was
自艾森豪威尔以来，他一直是美国历任总统的顾问。 他是
an early founder of NRO. I mean, our one
NRO的早期创始人之一。 我的意思是，
of our most classified agencies. His
我们最机密的机构之一。 他的
opinion matters. And while he didn't
意见很重要。 虽然他不想
want to be specific, he gave me sort of
说得具体些，但
metaphor when he spoke of the mad king
他谈到疯王
and the mad king with a nuclear arsenal.
和拥有核武库的疯王时，给了我一个非常有趣、近乎诗意的比喻。
And he even uses that French phrase
他甚至还用了法语词组“
deluge.
deluge”（洪水）。
This idea of like after me the flood. If
这种感觉就像洪水过后我一样。
I die, who cares? And I interpreted that
我死了，谁在乎呢？ 我的理解是，
that Garwin was talking about North
加文指的是
Korea because North Korea is the rogue
朝鲜，因为朝鲜是一个流氓的
nuclear armed nation that regularly sets
核武器国家，经常
off ballistic missiles and doesn't tell
发射弹道导弹却不告诉
anyone. There is an unspoken reality
任何人。 其他国家之间存在一种不成文的约定，即
people when you're going to test an ICBM
当你要用模拟弹头测试洲际弹道导弹时，你应该通知相关人员
with a dummy warhead. Of course, North
。 当然，
Korea doesn't adhere to that. So, you
朝鲜并不遵守这些规定。 所以，你
know, h when I interviewed people who
知道，当我采访那些
are in those command and control
在指挥控制
bunkers, those first 100 seconds we
掩体里的人时，最初的 100 秒我们
spoke of where the ballistic missile is
讨论的是弹道导弹的飞行路线，
on its way and and and all of that
所有
command and control is focused on is
指挥控制的重点都放在它是朝
this coming at us or is it as launching
我们飞来，还是发射
a space satellite or is it going into
一颗太空卫星，或者它是飞向
the Sea of Japan? That's what North
日本海。 这就是
Korea does. They don't announce those
朝鲜的做法。 他们不会公布这些
tests. And so imagine the anxiety in
测试结果。 因此，你可以想象
those command bunkers every time they
每次发射弹道导弹时，那些指挥掩体里的人们该有多么焦虑
launch a ballistic missile. They have
。 从 2022 年开始的 18 个月内，他们
launched a more than 100 ballistic
发射了 100 多枚弹道导弹
2022 forward.
。
Testing.
测试。
Okay. Testing. So this is so dangerous
好的。 测试。 所以，这非常危险，
and so rogue if there you know on the
也非常不负责任。
one hand I say there are no rules to
一方面，我认为
nuclear war but there are a few nuclear
核战争没有规则，但
rules to nuclear deterrence like you
核威慑有一些规则，比如你要
tell your neighbors and that's why I
告诉你的邻国，这就是我
chose North Korea but just to finish
选择朝鲜的原因。
that the sequence
最后，
the president launches 82 missiles at
总统向朝鲜发射了82枚导弹
North Korea in a counterattack
进行反击，
and that is and in the scenario that I
这就是我所
write the failure here now becomes about
描述的情景。现在，失败的原因变成了沟通不畅，这是
miscommunication a very important
一个非常重要的
concept and also about technology not
概念，也变成了技术
working and I source in the book
故障。我在书中
precisely where this information comes
明确指出了这些信息的来源
from. So Russia
。 所以俄罗斯
misinterprets
误认为
our launching nuclear weapons at North
我们对朝鲜发射核武器是对
Korea as being launched at Russia. Why?
俄罗斯发射的。 为什么？
because actual fact our ICBMs do not
因为事实上我们的洲际弹道导弹射程不够，无法在
to travel to North Korea without
不
overflying Russia.
飞越俄罗斯领空的情况下抵达朝鲜。
And so imagine in a climate like now
因此，试想一下，在当前这种
with hostilities as an all-time high,
敌对情绪达到历史最高点的环境下，
the Russian president just saying,
俄罗斯总统竟然说：
"Okay, well maybe they're not coming for
“好吧，也许他们不会来找
us." And nuclear policy, the policy of
我们。” 而核政策，也就是
deterrence is you launch if someone's
威慑政策，就是如果有人
launching at you. And so that is where
攻击你，你才进行反击。 所以，
you know in the second act of the book
你知道，在这本书的第二幕中，
endgame. Russia launches and Russia
最后 24 分钟就是 24 分钟 24 分钟。 俄罗斯发射，俄罗斯
launches. You don't la if someone's
发射。 如果有人
attacking you with nuclear missiles. You
用核导弹攻击你，你可就没办法了。 你
don't launch
不会
one or two back. That's mad king logic.
向后发射一两个。 这是疯王的逻辑。
You launch the motherload. And that's
你启动了母体。 这就是
what I have Russia launch in this
我设想中俄罗斯会采取的行动
scenario.
。
What do you mean mad king logic?
你说的“疯王逻辑”是什么意思？
Well, mad king logic is
嗯，疯王的逻辑是：
why would you do that?
你为什么要这么做？   是的
Yeah. Yeah.
。 是的。
Okay. So, in the book in the mad king
好的。 所以，按照书中那种疯狂国王的
logic of the book, the leader of North
逻辑，朝鲜的无名领导人出于
reasons we don't know and we will never
我们不知道也永远不会
know because history will end. The
知道的原因，向美国发射了一枚核武器，因为历史将会终结。
ability to write history ends in 72
书写历史的能力在
minutes of the book.
这本书的72分钟内就结束了。
So we will never know why and that is
所以我们永远不会知道为什么，这就是那种
the sort of you know question. Mad King
让人困惑的问题。  “疯王”的
logic is very different than defense
逻辑与
department logic or in many regards
国防部的逻辑，或者在很多方面与
Russian nuclear command and control
俄罗斯的核指挥控制
logic which I interview sort of the
逻辑截然不同。我采访了
world's expert on those subjects to be
这方面的世界级专家，以便让
able to you know give readers quickly an
读者能够快速了解
idea of what that logic is and why it
这种逻辑是什么，以及为什么它
has held for 79 years.
已经持续了79年。
Can't we just shoot it out the sky?
我们难道不能直接把它从天上打下来吗？
That is the great fantasy that is a
那是一种谬论，也是一种极大的幻想
fallacy. Right. So, let's talk numbers
。 正确的。 那么，我们来简单谈谈数字吧
for a second. America has 1,770
。 美国有1770枚
nuclear weapons on ready for launch
核武器处于随时可以发射的
status. They're deployed. Okay? They can
状态。 它们已被部署。 好的？ 它们可以
launch in seconds, minutes. Maybe some
在几秒钟或几分钟内发射。 或许有些
of the bombers take an hour or two.
轰炸机需要一两个小时才能完成。
Russia has roughly the same 1,674.
俄罗斯的人口数量大致相同，为 1,674 人。
That's the parity of the nuclear
这就是核条约的对等原则
treaties. That says nothing of the
。 更何况
thousands more that we each have in
我们每个人还有成千上万的
reserve. But those are actual nuclear
储备金。 但那些是真正的
weapons that are pointed at one another,
核武器，它们彼此对峙，随时
ready to go. Ready to go. Okay, so those
准备发射。 准备出发。 好的，根据这些
numbers,
数字，
the US has an interceptor program to
美国有一个拦截器计划，
allegedly intercept a long range
据称可以拦截远程
ballistic missile. I'm not talking about
弹道导弹。 我说的不是
short range or even medium range. Long
短程，甚至也不是中程。 这种远程攻击
range like that would come from Russia
通常来自俄罗斯
or North Korea. We have 44
或朝鲜。 我们有44枚
interceptor missiles. Four of them are
拦截导弹。 其中四人驻扎
at Vandenberg Air Force Base in Santa
在圣巴巴拉的范登堡空军基地
Barbara. 40 of them are at Fort Gley in
。 其中 40 人驻扎在
Alaska. 44. So if Russia has 1,670
阿拉斯加的格利堡。  44. 如果俄罗斯拥有 1670 枚
nuclear weapons, how are our 44
核武器，我们 44 枚
interceptors going to go up against
拦截导弹要如何对抗
those? And that and that says nothing,
它们？
by the way. And I get into this in sort
顺便说一句，那句话其实什么也没说明。 我之所以会深入探讨这个问题，是因为我了解到了
inside a nuclear warhead.
核弹头内部的一些小问题。
Many of them are what are called MVED,
其中许多是所谓的多弹头爆炸装置（MVED），
which means they have multiple warheads
这意味着它们内部装有多个弹头
inside of it. And so when the warhead
。 因此，当弹头
unleashes, the multiple warheads go out
释放时，多个弹头会
along with decoys so that if an
与诱饵一起发射出去，这样，如果
interceptor missile is coming at it, it
拦截导弹飞来，就能
greatly reduces the chance that the
大大降低
interceptor will be able to shoot it out
拦截导弹将其击落的几率
of the sky. The way that it was said to
。 别人是这样跟
me was like this. an interceptor
我说的。 拦截
missile, which is basically just like a
导弹，它基本上就跟
small ICBM, right? It's a small rock.
小型洲际弹道导弹一样，对吧？ 这是一块小石头。
It's a rocket.
这是一枚火箭。
It
这就像
is like trying to shoot a bullet with a
试图用子弹射击子弹一样
bullet. That's a quote from the
。 这是
spokesperson of at the Pentagon.
五角大楼发言人的原话。
One of them is traveling at 14,000 mph,
其中之一，即弹道导弹，正以每小时 14,000 英里的速度飞行
the ballistic missile. 14,000 mph. The
。 时速 14,000 英里。
interceptor, the little kinetic vehicle
拦截器，也就是
inside of it that's going to hit the
里面那个要撞击
warhead hopefully is traveling at 20,000
弹头的微型动能飞行器，速度有望达到
miles an hour. That's where you get the
每小时 20,000 英里。 这就好比
trying to hit a bullet with a bullet.
试图用子弹击中子弹一样。
And by the way, this is all happening
顺便说一句，这一切都发生在
500 miles up in space. Good luck. The
距离地面 500 英里的太空中。 祝你好运。
success rate of our interceptor program
我们的拦截器计划的成功率
is between 40 and 55%. That's on a good
在 40% 到 55% 之间。 那是在一切顺利的情况下，
day where they're testing these things
他们进行测试时会
and they go, "Hey, we're doing an
说：“嘿，我们正在进行
interceptor test. It might be around
拦截器测试。可能就在
there, right? That's called a curated
附近，对吧？”这叫做精心策划的
test. That's not in the madness of the
测试。那不是在混乱的
moment.
瞬间。
The bombs land.
炸弹落下。
If I was a
如果我是一只
fly on the wall, not that there would be
苍蝇，就在旁边看着——当然，那时
a war left, what would I what would I
战争已经结束了——我会看到什么？
and I was looking at America or the UK
我会看到美国或英国在遭受
nuclear bombs by thousands of, you know,
数千枚
Russian or North Korean nuclear weapons.
俄罗斯或朝鲜核武器的袭击之后的景象。
What would I see? What would the visuals
我会看到什么？
be in those minutes after the strike?
袭击发生后的几分钟内，我会看到什么画面？
I describe the first bomb in the
我描述了袭击五角大楼的第一枚炸弹
scenario that strikes the Pentagon. It's
。那是
a 1 megaton thermonuclear bomb in
一枚100万吨级的热核炸弹，我极其细致地描述了它可怕的后果
painstaking horrific detail. all sourced
。所有信息都
from Defense Department documents,
来自国防部的文件，以及
defense scientists who have worked for
国防科学家们数
decades to describe precisely what
十年来对
happens to things and to humans. And
物体和人类所受影响的精确描述。
it's horrifying. But on top of the
这令人毛骨悚然。但除了
initial flash of thermonuclear light,
最初的热核闪光——温度高达
which is 180 million degrees, which
1.8亿度——会
catches everything on fire in a 9mm
点燃一切之外…… 直径9毫米的
diameter radius. On top of the
半径。除了强
bulldozing effect of the wind and all
风的推土机效应，所有
the buildings coming down and more fires
建筑物倒塌，以及更多火灾
igniting more fires, on top of the
引发更多火灾之外，再加上
radiation poisoning people to death in
辐射中毒，
minutes and hours and days and weeks if
即使有人侥幸幸存，也会在几分钟、几小时、几天甚至几周内死亡
they happen to have survived. On top of
。除此之外
all of that, each one of these fires
，每一场火灾都会
creates a mega fire that is a hundred or
演变成一场面积达百平方英里甚至更大的超级大火
more square miles. And so essentially in
。所以
essence, what do you see? Well, in the
，本质上，你会看到什么？在第
scenario at minute 72, a thousand
72分钟的情景中，一千枚
Russian nuclear weapons land on the
俄罗斯核武器落在
United States. And so it just becomes a
美国。于是，一切都变成了一场
conflration of fire. It's just fire,
熊熊烈火。到处都是火，
fires burning, fires, 100, 200 square
燃烧的火焰，100、200
mile fires burning. And then we move
平方英里的火焰在燃烧。然后，我们就
into nuclear winter. And that's sort of
进入了核冬天。这
the day num malt of the book where I
本书的重点就在这里，我将从
point of view of one of the original
一位最初
nuclear winter paper with Carl Sean back
与卡尔·肖恩
in 1983. And his name is Professor Brian
在1983年共同撰写核冬天论文的科学家的角度来讲述核冬天。他的名字是布莱恩·
June and he spent the decades since
琼教授，此后几十年，他一直致力于最先进的
climate modeling systems that can now
气候研究。 现在有了能够
precisely tell us what nuclear winter
精确预测核冬天
will look like. cuz I've always thought,
景象的建模系统。因为我一直觉得，
that bad if, you know, Russia launched a
如果俄罗斯
thousand of their nuclear bombs at the
向美国发射一千枚核弹，
United States and I was here in New York
而我当时就在纽约，那核战争其实也没那么糟糕。
where I am now. I would die instantly.
我会立刻死去。
So, I wouldn't really know it had
这样，我甚至都不会知道战争已经
happened.
发生过。
Is that true?
是这样吗？
I think you would want to die instantly.
我想你会希望立刻死去。
the former um premier of the Soviet
苏联前总理尼基塔·克鲁夫
Union and he said after nuclear war the
说过，核战争之后，
survivors would envy the dead
幸存者会羡慕死者，
because there is right there is this
因为你会有一种
sense of if you survived I mean there is
感觉：如果你活了下来，那就意味着
no more law and order there is no more
没有法律和秩序，没有
rule of law there is no government Craig
法治，没有政府。克雷格·
Fugate made that very clear the bunkers
富盖特非常清楚地指出，
that the people in the military command
军事指挥
and control centers would be in, let's
控制中心的人员会躲进掩体，
say, the secret bunkers, not the ones
比如说，那些秘密掩体，不是
take out that I write about in the book.
我在书中提到的那些俄罗斯要摧毁的目标掩体。
But the smaller ones, those are going to
而是那些较小的掩体，它们
only function for as long as there's
只有在有
gasoline to run the diesel and the
汽油供应的情况下才能继续运转。 柴油和
diesel generators. And then those people
柴油发电机。然后这些人
are going to have to come out. And who's
就得出来。剩下的是谁
left? It's man returning to the most
？人类回归到最
primal, most violent state as people
原始、最暴力的状态，为了
remain. And by the way, they're all
仅存的微薄资源而争斗。顺便说一句，他们都
malnourished, everybody's sick, and most
营养不良，每个人都病倒了，大多数
people have lost everything and everyone
人失去了一切，失去了所有
they know. How's that going to feel?
认识的人。那会是什么感觉？
It's going to feel as you describe here
就像你
on page 277.
在第277页描述的那样。
There are a thousand flashes of light
成千上万道闪光将
superheating the air in each ground.
地面上的空气加热到极高的温度。从
Zero to 180 million degrees Fahrenheit.
零到1.8亿华氏度。
A thousand fireballs each more than a
成千上万个直径超过一
mile in diameter.
英里的火球。
A thousand steeply fronted blast waves.
成千上万道陡峭的冲击波。
A thousand walls of compressed air. A
成千上万道压缩空气墙。
thousand American cities and towns where
成千上万个美国城镇，
five, six or seven miles radius change
方圆五六七英里内的所有人工建筑都发生了
physical shapes collapse and burn. A
物理变化，坍塌燃烧。
thousand cities and towns with molten
成千上万个城镇，
asphalt streets. A thousand cities and
沥青街道熔化。成千上万个
towns with survivors impaled to death by
城镇，幸存者被
flying debris. A thousand cities and
飞溅的碎片刺穿而死。成千上万个
towns filled with tens of millions of
城镇，数千万人的
dead people. With tens of millions of
尸体堆积如山。 数千万
unfortunate survivors suffering fatal
不幸的幸存者遭受致命的
thirdderee burns. People naked,
三重烧伤。人们赤身裸体，
tattered, bleeding, and suffocating.
衣衫褴褛，鲜血淋漓，窒息而亡。
People who don't look or act like people
他们不再像人，也不再像人
anymore.
。
Across America and Europe, hundreds of
在整个美洲和欧洲，
millions of people are dead and dying
数亿人死亡或濒临死亡，
while hundreds of military aircraft fly
而数百架军用飞机在
circles in the air until they until they
空中盘旋，直到
run out of fuel.
燃料耗尽。
I mean, that is
我的意思是，这
that is some visual.
画面太可怕了。
do you think after those 72 minutes?
你认为72分钟后会有多少人死亡或濒临死亡？
Hundreds of millions of people die
数亿人死于
in the fireballs. No question. But the
火球之中。毫无疑问。但
number that I think is very interesting
我认为一个非常有趣的数字
to think about comes from Professor Tune
来自图恩教授
and his team who wrote a paper for
和他的团队，他们
nature uh recently 2022 and sort of
最近在2022年为《自然》杂志撰写了一篇论文，
updated nuclear winter idea based around
更新了基于食物的核冬天理论，
food and the number that they have is 5
他们得出的数字是50
billion people would be dead.
亿人死亡。
The population of the planet currently
地球目前的人口
is what 8 billion.
是80亿。
Yes. So there'd be three billion people
是的。所以会有30亿人
still alive.
幸存。
Where shall I go to be one of the three
我该去哪里才能成为这30
billion? I was I was just in New Zealand
亿人中的一员呢？我刚刚去过新西兰
and Australia.
和澳大利亚。
That's exactly where you'd go. Although
那里正是你最有可能幸存的地方。 去吧。虽然
according to tune, those are the only
根据图恩教授的说法，只有那些
places that could actually sustain
地方才真正能够维持
agriculture.
农业。
I was there two weeks ago, not even two
我两周前去过那里，不，应该说不到
weeks ago. It was maybe 10 days ago. I
两周前，大概是十天前。当时我
was in New Zealand and Australia and at
在新西兰和澳大利亚，
I think Iran attacked
我想那时候伊朗袭击了
Israel. Yes.
以色列。是的，
I was kind of happy.
我当时还挺高兴的。
You were in the right place at the right
你真是恰好在对的时间出现在了对的地方
time.
。
I was kind of happy for where I was
我当时也挺庆幸自己
located. If I'm you know I was thinking
身处那里。你知道，我记得
I actually remember talking to my
我当时在想，我跟
friends and I pulled up a map and I was
朋友们聊天的时候，还打开了一张地图，
trying to see how far away I was from
想看看我离
everything. I was thinking if cuz World
所有地方有多远。我在想，因为
War II started trending on Twitter. I
二战在推特上开始成为热门话题了。我
was thinking if if it does break out
在想，如果
now, I think I'm probably pretty well
现在爆发战争，我想我的
placed. Is that the place to be?
位置应该相当不错。那里是应该待的地方吗？
That is that is according to Professor
这是图恩教授说的
Tune. I mean, he was so generous with
。我的意思是，他真的非常慷慨
me. He shared a lot of his slideshows
。他跟我分享了很多
that he has for his students and that is
他给学生准备的幻灯片，那
really pretty much what's left. I mean
基本上就是剩下的全部了。我的意思是，
because most of the world is certainly
因为世界上大部分地区，尤其是
the mid latitudes would be covered in
中纬度地区，都会被
these you know sheets of ice the the
冰层和
freshwater bodies and places like Iowa
淡水水体覆盖。 像爱荷华州、英国
and UK Ukraine would be would be just
和乌克兰这样的地方，将会被
snow for 10 years and so agriculture
大雪覆盖长达十年，农业
would fail and when agriculture fails
将会崩溃。农业崩溃会导致
people just die and on on top of that
人口死亡。更糟糕的是，
the ozone layer will be so damaged and
臭氧层遭到严重破坏，人们
that you can't be outside in the
无法在
sunlight
阳光下活动，从而面临辐射中毒的风险。
and so people will be forced to live
人们将被迫生活在
underground and so you have to imagine
地下，你可以想象，
food everywhere except for in New
除了
Zealand and Australia. Um there was also
新西兰和澳大利亚以外，其他地方的人们都将生活在地下，为了食物而战。
another interesting detail that that he
他
shared with me that you know 66 million
还跟我分享了一个有趣的细节：6600万
years ago an asteroid hit earth and
年前，一颗小行星撞击地球，导致
wiped out the dinosaurs and something
恐龙和大约
like 70% of the known species
70%的已知物种灭绝。图恩
and professor tune compared nuclear war
教授将核战争
to that situation
与这种情况进行了比较。
and so when you really think about it
仔细想想，联邦紧急
FEMA's director.
事务管理局局长克雷格·富盖特也表达了同样的观点。
You think about it, there's nothing we
想想看，我们
can do about an asteroid,
对小行星撞击无能为力，
at least not right now. And yet, there
至少现在无能为力。然而，我们
is something. Nuclear war is a man-made
并非束手无策。核战争是人为造成的
threat. And therefore, it has to be a
威胁，因此，也必须找到
man-made solution.
人为的解决方案。那么，
What is the solution?
解决方案是什么呢？
I really believe that people motivate
我坚信，人们…… 激励
other people. It's like a fundamental
他人。这就像一条基本
truth on the smallest scale and on the
真理，无论在最小的层面还是
biggest scale. And so there's one person
最大的层面都是如此。因此，有一个人
who is incredibly powerful and that is
拥有极其强大的权力，那就是
the president of the United States. For
美国总统。无论
better or for worse, it's just the way
好坏，事实就是如此
it is. And so in the same way that the
。正如
president has presidential sole
总统拥有
authority to start a nuclear war, the
发动核战争的唯一权力一样，
president also has a very powerful pen
总统也拥有一支非常强大的笔，
with which he can write executive
可以签署
orders, an EO. And the story I tell on
行政命令（EO）。我接下来要讲的故事
the hopeful note goes like this. When I
是这样的：
was in high school in 1983, there was an
1983年我还在上高中时，
ABC TV movie called The Day After.
ABC电视台播出了一部名为《浩劫之后》（The Day After）的电视电影。
And it showed a fictional war between
它讲述了一场虚构的
the United States and then Soviet
美国与
Russia. It was horrific and terrifying.
苏联之间的战争。场面惨烈，令人恐惧。
Okay. 100 million Americans watched it.
一亿美国人观看了这部电影。
A 100 millions Americans. It was like
一亿美国人！这相当于当时美国
the third of a the population.
人口的三分之一。
And I think it was half the population
我想当时应该是半数人口
then. Um, President Reagan was one of
。里根总统也是其中之一
those Americans. He had a private
。他在戴维营举行了一场私人
screening at Camp David. His adviserss
放映会。他的顾问
told him not to watch it. He did watch
劝他不要看。但他还是看了
it. Before that, President Reagan was a
。在那之前， 里根总统是个
hawk. He was pro- nuclear weapons. His
鹰派。他支持核武器。他的
position was the more nuclear weapons,
立场是核武器
the better. He was the one putting
越多越好。正是他
nuclear weapons in space with the Star
通过“
Wars program, the SDI program. Okay? He
星球大战”计划和“战略防御倡议”（SDI）计划将核武器送入太空。明白吗？他简直
couldn't have been more pro- deterrence
不能更支持威慑
supremacy.
优势了。但核战争爆发
He saw the day after and he changed his
后，他改变了
position. He wrote in his White House
立场。他在白宫日记中写道，
journal that he became greatly
他感到非常
depressed. his words
沮丧。
and he reached out to Gorbachoff and
他与戈尔巴乔夫进行了沟通，
then they had a Rekavik summit, a summit
之后他们在冰岛举行了雷科维克峰会。里根
in Iceland, Reagan and Gorbachoff and
和戈尔巴乔夫
through communication, right? Through
通过沟通，
both of them realizing this is madness,
意识到这是疯狂之举，
realizing what could happen, seeing the
意识到可能发生的后果，预见了核战争爆发
day after and realizing my god, this
后的情景，意识到天哪，这绝对
cannot happen. And they famously issued
不能发生。他们发表了一份著名的
a statement that said a nuc joint
联合声明，即关于
said a nuclear war cannot be won and
核战争的声明，指出核战争无法取胜，也
must never be fought. And the result of
绝不能打。
the Rekovik summit was that the world
雷科维克峰会的结果是，世界
has gone from 70,000 nuclear warheads.
核弹头数量从7万枚减少到7000枚。
That was the all-time high. 70,000
这是历史最高水平。7万枚，
Why do you need 70,000 nuclear warheads?
为什么还需要核弹头？  7万枚核弹头？
That's what there were in 1986. And now
那是1986年的数量。而现在，
here we are because of the reductions,
由于削减、
because of the treaties, thanks to those
由于条约，由于那
two
两枚
approximately nuclear warheads. That is
大约12500枚的核弹头，我们才有了今天的成就。这是朝着
the movement in the right direction. And
正确方向迈出的一步。
it came from a dramatic story being told
这源于一个引人入胜的故事，
and it came from the president taking
源于总统采取的
action because people would not stand
行动，因为人们再也无法容忍
for this anymore. There were massive
这种情况。当时爆发了大规模的
protests. Do you believe we can ever get
抗议活动。你认为我们最终能实现
to zero? Honestly,
零核弹头吗？说实话，
that is for the disarmament experts. I
这应该由裁军专家来回答。我更
like to stay in my lane as a
喜欢专注于
storyteller, as an investigative
讲故事，专注于调查
journalist. I like to give you the
记者的工作。我喜欢先给你们提供一些
dramatic fast read and then pass the
引人入胜的快节奏信息，然后把
baton to those who have been working on
接力棒交给那些
that issue for decades because boy are
几十年来一直致力于此的人，因为
they qualified. I just had the great
他们确实有资格。我非常
fortune of being invited to Brussels
幸运地受邀前往布鲁塞尔，参加了
where I was part of a nuclear expo and
一个核能博览会，
there were members of the European
欧洲
Parliament in the audience and I and and
议会的议员们也在现场，还有很多
there were all these disarmament people
裁军人士。
there and I learned a lot about all of
我了解了很多关于
these groups and they have the answer
这些团体的信息，他们掌握着答案，
and they are the ones that should be
他们才是真正能解决问题的人。 应该有人
asked that question and they are doing a
问这个问题，而且他们正在为此做
lot to get us there.
很多努力。
From the moment you wrote the first word
从你写下
in this new book um nuclear war scenario
这本关于核战争场景的新书的第一个字，
to when you finished the book, how did
到你完成整本书，
your feelings change about the subject
你对这个主题的感受发生了怎样的变化
matter?
？
It's interesting because
这很有意思，因为
you you write the this is just my
你写的是“这只是我
experience as a journalist, but you you
作为一名记者的经历”，但你
write the book and you're like any
写这本书的时候，就像任何一个
professional person, you want to do a
专业人士一样，你想把
really good job at your job, right? So,
自己的工作做得尽善尽美，对吧？所以，
so I was very focused on gathering the
我非常专注于收集
facts and then relaying them in a
事实，然后以一种
readable way. You know, my husband Kevin
易于理解的方式呈现出来。你知道，我的丈夫凯文
always says like you got to write
总是说，你得写
something that someone can read on the
一些人们可以在
beach or an airplane, right? Which is
海滩上或飞机上阅读的东西，对吧？这
not necessarily conducive to like Nazi
未必适用于像纳粹
scientists or the other things I've
科学家或我写过的其他内容
written about. But for this, it became
。但就这本书而言，我
clear to me nuclear launch to nuclear
清楚地意识到，
winter fast. Have people read it fast
要让人们快速阅读，
because you want to grab their attention
因为你想抓住他们的注意力，
because I'm a mother, you know, I'm a
因为我是一位母亲，你知道，我是一个
hopeful person that believes that we do
充满希望的人，我相信我们
not have to live with this threat
不必生活在这种威胁之下
overhead. And so my focus of the work
。所以，我工作的重点
was really on doing the best job I could
是尽我所能做到最好。
to narrate the story. And I think you
叙述故事。我觉得你对
um maybe any more sort of emotional or
任何情感或
sentimental feelings. You try to you try
感伤的情绪都不太在意。你试图把
to push that into the pros I suppose. So
这些情绪压抑到文章的客观层面。所以，
maybe in subtext
也许在字里行间存在着
there is a sense of urgency and and even
一种紧迫感，甚至是
fear but for me intellectually you know
恐惧感。但对我来说，
as an investigative journalist it was it
作为一名调查记者，从理智上讲，我只是想知道
was just what's what's the next page
下一页会
going to read like
写些什么。
but how do you feel about you know the
不过，你对
nature of you it's interesting as well
自己的性格有什么看法呢？这很有意思，
because you when you think about the
因为想想
books you've written I I think how many
你写过的书，我想
have you written now six or seven seven
你现在一共写了多少本？六七
books in total the subject matter of
本？
your books are
你书的主题是
the basis of a lot of conspiracy theory,
很多阴谋论的基础，
if that makes sense. You know, you've
如果我这么说你能理解的话。你知道，你
written about Area 51 and this thing
写过关于51区、
called Operation Paperclip and the
回形针行动、
Pentagon and and now nuclear bombs and
五角大楼、核弹和
the CIA, all these kinds of things which
中央情报局等等，这些都是
theories that I hear hear about. Um, so
我听到的许多阴谋论的基础。所以，
you've you've got a very unique
你对世界有着非常独特的
perspective on the world because you've
视角，因为你…… 能够
interviewing some of the most
采访到一些最
interesting people that are closest to
有趣、最了解
these very interesting subjects. What
这些有趣话题的人，这本身就是一种荣幸和机会。
are some of the things that you've come
你有没有
to learn that you once thought were just
了解到一些你曾经认为只是
conspiracy theories?
阴谋论的事情？
I mean, conspiracy theory is such a
我的意思是，“阴谋论”这个
loaded word and I think it's too bad
词含义很重，我觉得很可惜，
that um it's used as a catchall to kind
它被当作一个万能的标签，用来
of dismiss
否定
uh a lot of curiosity
很多好奇心，
because curiosity is important, right?
因为好奇心很重要，对吧？
And curiosity leads toward reading. I
而好奇心会引导我们去阅读。我
mean, I couldn't be a bigger fan of
是说，我非常喜欢
reading or listening to p, you know,
阅读或听播客，也就是
educating yourself. I mean, things have
自我教育。
really changed in terms of audio. Like,
音频方面真的发生了很大的变化。比如，
you can listen to a podcast and learn a
你可以听播客学到
lot. You can listen to an audio book the
很多东西。你可以像以前阅读书籍一样听有声书
them. And and so to just call things
。所以，仅仅把所有事情都称为
conspiracy
阴谋
theories, I find to be intellectually
论，我觉得这种说法缺乏深度
thin, right? It's just too easy. And
，对吧？太简单粗暴了。而且
it's also very self-righteous. And I
也显得很自以为是。
think two things I always work to avoid
我一直努力避免的两件事就是：一是表现得像个
kind of being a know-it-all. And I am
万事通。我
around a lot of know-it-alls because
身边有很多…… 很多自以为是的
people who become experts in subjects um
人，因为那些成为某个领域的专家，
and maybe they don't get as much
也许他们得到的
attention as they think they deserve
关注不如自己认为应得的那么多，
tend to become a little bit of
往往会变得有点
self-righteous know-it-alls. And so I
自以为是。所以我必须在
have to wind my way through that world
这个圈子里摸索前进，
because I'm always what interests me are
因为我总是对那些
subjects that make me ask the question
让我追问“
why, right? Like why does no one know
为什么”的话题感兴趣，对吧？比如，为什么没人知道51
about Area what why why is Area 51 so
区？为什么51区如此
secret? I mean when I wrote the book
神秘？我的意思是，当我写《
Area 51, the word Area 51 was still
51区》这本书的时候，“51区”这个词还是
classified.
机密。
You couldn't say it. I went to the CIA
你不能说。我去中央情报局，
and I was told by my minder, if you say
我的保镖告诉我，如果你说出
a certain word and number,
某个特定的词和数字，就会被
you will be asked to leave. It was
请出去。它当时是
classified. It only became unclassified
机密。
when President Obama spoke about it
直到奥巴马总统公开谈论它，它才被解密
publicly.
。
Oh, really?
哦，真的吗？
He just mentioned it and then it was
他只是提了一下，然后就
unclassified. Right. And so
解密了。是的。所以
to answer your question, um
回答你的问题，
I find it really interesting tackling
我发现研究那些符合
subjects that are in the zeitgeist that
时代精神、
people are interested in and then trying
人们感兴趣的话题，然后试图
to unpack
揭开
the truths and the fictions. But is
真相和谎言，真的很有意思。但是……
there something you heard about, you
你听说过一些事，一些传闻，
you thought that can't possibly be true
你觉得这不可能是真的，
and then after doing a little bit of
但经过一番
investigative researching and
调查研究和
journalism, you discovered that it
新闻报道后，你发现这
actually was true and you were blown
竟然是真的，你简直震惊了
away. And I say that in part because I
。我这么说，部分原因是我以前一直觉得
lot of these subjects, era 51, the CIA,
很多关于51时代、中央情报局、间谍活动等等的
this idea that there's all these spies
说法都是无稽之谈
and they're doing all of this stuff. And
。
I thought a lot of it was
我以为很多都
just internet rumors and you know people
只是网络谣言，或者某些人——你知道，就是那种
heads and they're just like whatever.
脑子里装着锡箔纸的人——才会说这些。
And then I had the privilege of speaking
后来我有幸
to some people on this podcast and just
在这个播客节目里和一些
out there in the world who confirmed
普通人交流，他们证实了
that a lot of the things I once thought
我以前认为的很多阴谋
were tinfoil hat stuff is actually true.
论都是真的。
And once once you have the curtain
一旦你
pulled back, it kind of blows your mind
揭开了真相，你的思维就会被彻底颠覆，你会开始思考还有
open to what else could be true. And I'm
什么可能是真的。我这个
I'm a person that kind of like needs
人比较注重
evidence and logic. And I'm not going to
证据和逻辑，我不会
believe something because I saw it on
因为……就相信。 我是在
like a Instagram post or a story or
Instagram帖子、故事或者
Telegram community, but my mind's been
Telegram社群里看到的，但
blown especially over the last couple of
过去几年里，我尤其震惊于
years about how um how some of these
一些
things that people consider to be
人们认为是
conspiracy theories are actually very
阴谋论的事情，实际上却非常
true. Have you had those moments in your
真实。你的职业生涯中也有过这样的时刻吗
career?
？
Oh, absolutely. But I mean, you can
哦，当然。我的意思是，你可以
really drill down on this stuff and
深入研究这些东西，
figure out the thematic element of
找出事件的主题元素，
what's going on and then the specifics.
然后再深入细节。
And I'll give you an example. Like in
我举个例子。比如在
Area 51, I learned about something
51区，我了解到一种
called strategic deception, which is a
叫做“战略欺骗”的概念，这是
CIA concept. Okay? And this plays into
中央情报局（CIA）的一个概念。好吗？这和
conspiracy theories. And when you come
阴谋论有关。当你
across something, maybe having this
遇到某些事情时，也许
information I'm about to tell you will
我接下来要告诉你的信息能
help you go, okay, let me look at it in
帮助你从这
terms of these two lanes. So it goes
两个角度来看待它。事情是这样的：
like this. The CIA had a was building
CIA
spy planes out at Area 51. The U2 spy
在51区建造间谍飞机，也就是U-2侦察机
plane, which was going to spy on the
，它计划
Soviet Union in the 50s from above and
在20世纪50年代从空中监视苏联，以
figure out whether they were preparing
查明他们是否在准备
for nuclear war. And the plane was built
核战争。 这架飞机是
at Area 51 because this no one could
在51区建造的，因为这样就绝对不能让任何人
know about it. It flew at 70,000 ft. It
知道。它的飞行高度是7万英尺，完全
was out of range of any surfaceto-air
超出了地对空导弹的射程
missiles. Um I interviewed the first man
。我采访了第一个驾驶
who flew over the Soviet Union in a U2,
U-2侦察机飞越苏联的人——
Hervey Stockman, and he took pictures
赫维·斯托克曼，他用
with these massive CIA cameras that you
CIA的大型相机拍摄了一些照片，这些照片后来都传回了
know came back to the agency. It was wet
CIA。这些相机是湿
film and allowed the CIA to understand
胶片相机，让CIA能够了解
in Soviet Russia. who was photographing
苏联地面上正在发生的事情，比如拍摄
military bases. So this spy plane was
军事基地。所以这架间谍飞机的
being built and it was so secret like
建造过程极其隐秘，
only the president knew about it. At the
只有总统才知道。与此同时，就在
exploded next door, right? So Area 51
隔壁的51区，核武器正在爆炸，对吧？51区
and then over at Area 23 was where the
和23区是
the bombs were going off and there was a
核弹爆炸的地方。
I was interviewing all the engineers who
我采访了所有参与
were building the spy plane and Bob
建造这架间谍飞机的工程师，鲍勃·
Murphy was one of the lead engineers and
墨菲是其中一位首席工程师，
he told me this story about strategic
他给我讲了一个关于战略
deception. So he and others would go to
欺骗的故事。他和一些同事会去那个被
the ranch, that's what they called Area
称为“牧场”的地方，也就是他们所说的
51. Then they'd fly back to Burbank,
51区。 他们会飞回加州伯班克
California, where they all lived for the
，他们周末都住在那里，和
weekends to be with their families. And
家人团聚。
they would take this shuttle back and
他们会乘坐班车往返
forth. And one day, um, they went to a
。有一天，嗯，他们
big party the night before and Bob
前一天晚上参加了一个大型派对，鲍勃·
Murphy got drunk. He was not a guy who
墨菲喝醉了。他平时不怎么
gets drunk, but he got drunk. He missed
喝酒，但那天他喝醉了。他错过了
the shuttle and he was like, "Oh my god,
班车，然后他说：“我的天哪，
I'm gonna lose my job. I'm in trouble."
我要丢工作了。”  “我遇到麻烦了。”
and he opens the door is how he
他跟我描述说，然后他打开门，
described it to me to like you know go
就像你知道的，
out and deal with this and there's a FBI
出去处理这件事，一个联邦调查局
agent like about to knock on the door
特工正要敲门，
and they tell and the guy turns white as
他们告诉了他，那家伙脸色
a ghost because Bob Murphy was supposed
惨白，因为鲍勃·墨菲原本应该在
to be on that flight so he was on the
那架飞机上，他的名字在
flight manifest and it crashed into
航班乘客名单上，飞机在飞往查尔斯顿的途中坠毁，机上
everyone was dead. Okay, so that is just
人员全部遇难。好吧，这本身就是
a dramatic thing to begin with but
一件很戏剧性的事情，但
here's how it ties up with strategic
它与战略欺骗的联系在于：
The CIA
中央情报局
learns that its aircraft full of U2
得知，他们那架满载U2
engineers, P designers, all these
工程师、P系列飞机设计师以及所有参与
incredibly important people on this top
这个
secret project are dead. They just
绝密项目的重要人员的飞机都遇难了。飞机刚刚
crashed into Mount Charleston.
坠毁在查尔斯顿山上。
What are they going to do? How are they
他们该怎么办？他们
going to keep this secret? All the news
要如何保守这个秘密？所有新闻
stations are racing up to the top of the
媒体都争先恐后地赶到
mountain to try to get to the crash
山顶，试图抵达坠机
site. Oh my god, this is going to be the
现场。我的天哪，这个
project's going to be blown open. what
项目要被彻底曝光了。
are we going to do? So, they quickly
我们该怎么办？于是，他们迅速
rope off the areas. They do the damage
封锁了现场。他们尽力进行损害
control to the best that they can, but
控制，但
they're spinning and I have all the
他们手忙脚乱，乱成一团。 我掌握了
declassified documents from that part of
那部分的所有解密文件
it, learning how worried they are.
，了解到他们有多么担忧。
There's no almost no doubt the project's
几乎可以肯定，这个项目
going to be revealed. The YouTube
将会曝光。YouTube
program is going to be no more because
项目将不复存在，因为
once the Soviets know about it, it's
一旦苏联人知道了，它就会被
off. And instead, the press
叫停。而媒体却
comes up with a story. The press reports
编造了一个故事。媒体报道
that it's all these atomic scientists
说，所有这些原子科学家都在
working on this secret new weap. They
秘密研发一种新型武器。
just completely make this up in essence,
本质上，他们完全是捏造的，
right? It's this new weapons project and
对吧？他们说这是一个新型武器项目，而
that's what they're all doing. Who knows
这就是他们都在做的事情。谁知道是
who put what bug in someone's ear? And
谁在谁的耳朵里放了窃听器？于是，这就是
so that's the story that comes out. And
流传出来的故事。而
the CIA is like
中央情报局简直
perfect. And what the story explains
完美。这个故事解释了
that there are two kinds of strategic
战略欺骗有两种方式
deception. There's cover. When you say,
。一种是掩饰。
like Bob Murphy said to his wife, "I'm
就像鲍勃·墨菲对他的妻子说的那样，“我
just a engineer working out there on
只是个在
some television systems." That's cover.
那儿研究电视系统的工程师。”这就是掩饰。
That was his cover. He didn't say, "I'm
这就是他的掩饰。他没有说，“我在
working on the U2 spy plane." And then
研究U-2侦察机。”另一种
there's disinformation
是虚假信息，
when the press reports that the crash
比如媒体报道坠机事件中
was full of a bunch of atomic engineers
充满了…… 一群原子工程师
working on a secret weapons program. And
在秘密研发武器项目。
those are both kinds of strategic
这两种情况都属于战略
deception. And so you begin to realize
欺骗。所以你会开始意识到，
that there is a purpose behind a lot of
很多公开的信息背后都有其目的，
and the CIA often uses that to his
而中央情报局经常利用这一点来达到自己的
advantage. And so whenever a situation
目的。因此，每当发生某种情况时
happens, you have to say to yourself, is
，你都必须扪心自问：事情的真相
this really what happened or is it
究竟如何？还是
covering up something else? And then of
另有隐情？
course you have to put your rational
当然，你还得保持理性，
person hat on and you can't just imagine
不能凭空想象
what the true story might be. You have
真相。你必须
to actually find it and report it.
找到真相并进行报道。
Does the CIA um or the I think in the UK
中央情报局，或者在英国，我记得好像
it's called MI5 or MI6. MI6 I think is
叫军情五处（MI5）或军情六处（MI6）。军情六处（MI6）应该和中央情报局差不多。军情六处（MI6）以及
secret service agencies around the world
世界各地所有这些特殊的秘密情报机构，会
do they work with the media?
和媒体合作吗？
That's a much that's a totally separate
这完全是另一个话题，可以单独做一个
podcast. We could talk forever because
播客来讨论。我们可以一直聊下去，因为
there's history of the CIA and I'm not
中央情报局的历史非常悠久。我对
an expert on foreign intelligence
外国情报
agencies as much as I am on the United
机构的了解不如对美国情报机构的了解那么深入
States, but by all means, there's a long
，但无论如何，
history of the CIA working with uh
中央情报局与
journalists, reporters, authors um to
记者、撰稿人和作家合作的历史由来已久。 嗯，把
put information there. I mean, there's
信息放在那里。我的意思是，
to my eye. The question is, you know,
在我看来，几乎没有什么事情是中央情报局没做过的。问题是，你知道，要把
how that's happening. I write about in
这些事情放在具体的背景下报道。我写过关于
the Pentagon's brain if you want a
五角大楼内部运作的文章，如果你想做
little homework, you know, and you go
点功课，可以去书的
into the back and in the index and look
后面，在索引里
up brainwashing
查找“洗脑”这个词，那里有一篇很
and there's a long story uh where I talk
长的文章，
to where I explain h exactly how this
我详细解释了
happened in the 50s with what ultimately
20世纪50年代这一切是如何发生的，以及最终演变成
an element that became known as the MK
MK
Ultra program. Okay. So, like MK Ultra
Ultra计划的那部分内容。好的。MK Ultra
was a real program and it had a lot of
是一个真实存在的计划，它包含很多
sinister components to it. Is it
险恶的成分。它真的像
everything that you know certain groups
某些被
of people that sometimes get called
称为
conspiracy theorists say that it was?
阴谋论者的人所说的那样吗？
No. But there are threads of truth in
不。但它确实包含一些真相
it. And if you reverse engineer the
。如果你从头开始反向推演
brainwashing concept from the back, you
洗脑的概念，你
will see what I'm talking about. And
就会明白我的意思。
it's I think it's a very interesting
我认为这是一个非常有趣的
story because it actually involves the
故事，因为它实际上涉及到了
head of the CIA, a guy called Alan
中央情报局局长艾伦·
Dulles and his son who got brain damaged
杜勒斯和他的儿子。
in Korea whom I tracked down and
我找到了一位在朝鲜战争中脑部受损的人，并
interviewed for that book. Spoiler
为了那本书采访了他。剧
alert,
透一下，
what happens?
发生了什么？
Which part I mean which part of
我是说，
I'm so I'm so compelled by this the
我为什么对
whole idea of the CIA because we we had
中央情报局（CIA）的整个概念如此着迷？因为我们最近请了一位
someone here recently talking we had
嘉宾——
Andrew here recently talking about what
安德鲁——来谈谈
goes on at the CIA and I think um he one
CIA的运作。他
of the things he said to me is that the
跟我说过，
role of the CIA has changed over time
CIA的角色随着时间推移发生了变化，
and once upon a time it was more capable
曾经它拥有更
of doing more things. And by the way he
强大的能力。但从他的
described it sounded like the CIA has
描述来看，CIA的
less powers and can do less of the
权力似乎有所下降，
things that it's been accused of in the
过去被指控的那些事情也少了
past. I think it's been accused of
。我记得有人指控CIA
killing the president here by some
刺杀了总统，
people or being involved in the
或者参与了
assassination of one of the presidents
刺杀某位总统的行动
here. Um, and does the CIA report
。CIA
directly into the president?
直接向总统汇报吗？
The CIA features in almost every one of
CIA几乎出现在
my books.
我的每一本书里。
I did at the CIA was a book called
我对CIA最全面的研究是一本名为《
Surprise, Kill, Vanish, which is about
突袭、杀戮、消失》（Surprise, Kill, Vanish）的书，这本书讲述的是
the CIA's paramilitary.
CIA的…… 准军事组织。
And once I reported that, I understood
我报道过之后才明白，
distinct components of the CIA. there's
中央情报局实际上由两个截然不同的部分组成。一个是
the sort of central intelligence agency,
中央情报机构，也就是
the primary um human, it's called human
主要的人力情报部门，包括
intelligence and there's analysts and
分析人员和
there's espionage and and then there's
间谍活动；另一个是
the paramilitary organization
准军事组织，它
which was set up in 1947
成立于1947年，
specifically to go against the Russian
专门用来对抗苏联的同类机构，
version of itself. sort of to do the
执行我们不得不做的那些最
darkest,
黑暗、最
dirtiest,
肮脏、最
nastiest operations that we had to
卑鄙的行动，
because the Russians were. And so, you
因为苏联人……所以，你
know, the CIA is a is a is a giant
知道，中央情报局是一个
organization with a lot of tentacles.
触角遍布的庞大组织。
And I think it's important to speak, at
我认为有必要谈谈这一点，
least for me, having reported on many of
至少对我而言，因为我报道过很多
these different programs. You know, Area
不同的项目。你知道，《
51 covers the aerial espionage element
51区》涵盖了中央情报局的空中间谍活动
of the CIA, the science and technology.
、科学技术方面的内容。
The CIA was responsible for putting the
中央情报局负责将
first satellite in space, the Corona
第一颗人造卫星送入太空，即“科罗娜”
program. Dr. Bud Won, who I interviewed
计划。我曾就《51区》采访过巴德·沃恩博士，他领导着
for Area 51, remarkable
卓越的
intelligence, surveillance, and
情报、监视和
reconnaissance programs. And then you
侦察项目。 你们
have the paramilitary operators, the
有准军事人员，
trigger pullers, uh the snake eataters,
扣动扳机的人，呃，就是那些“吃蛇者”，
the individuals who, you know, find,
那些负责找到、
fix, and finish people. That's a
解决、然后干掉目标的人。这是一种
euphemism.
委婉的说法。
um the teams that do that, but I prefer
嗯，我是说那些执行这些任务的团队，但我更喜欢
to speak very specifically on programs
具体谈论项目，
because I find it's the most
因为我觉得这是我能
it it's the most responsible or the most
最负责任、最
factual way for me to stick to a certain
客观地阐述
lane of the agency because it is so
机构特定领域的方式，毕竟机构的规模实在
vast.
太大了。
Once upon a time, if you had a business
以前，如果你有一个商业
idea, it was exceptionally difficult to
想法，启动起来会异常困难
get going. But now in the age of
。但现在有了
Shopify, it is exceptionally easy. As
Shopify，一切都变得异常简单。正如
many of you will know, Shopify are a
你们中的许多人所知，Shopify 是
sponsor of this podcast. If you don't
本播客的赞助商。如果你
know Shopify, it's an exceptionally
不了解 Shopify，它是一个极其
simple web platform for anybody that's
简单的网络平台，适合任何有
got an idea that wants to transact on a
想法并想在
global scale. So things like these
全球范围内进行交易的人。比如
conversation cards, which we sell, we've
我们销售的这种对话卡片，我们就是
sold using Shopify and it only took us a
用 Shopify 来销售的，只需要点击
couple of clicks to get going. So why
几下鼠标就能开始。那么
did we choose Shopify? for a number of
我们为什么选择 Shopify 呢？
reasons, but I think one of the big ones
原因有很多，但我认为其中一个
which goes unappreciated is their
被低估的重要原因是…… 他们的
checkout system converts 36% better
结账系统转化率
compared to other platforms. And here's
比其他平台高出 36%。为了帮
for you. If you go to
您省钱，我打算这样做：如果您访问
shopify.com/bartlet,
shopify.com/bartlet，
you'll be able to try Shopify for $1 a
就可以每月仅需 1 美元试用 Shopify
month. I've seen Shopify completely
。我亲眼见证了 Shopify 彻底
change people's lives, and for many of
改变了人们的生活，
you, I think it could change yours. On
我相信它也能改变你们中的许多人的生活。关于
the the nuclear war subject, we talked a
核战争的话题，我们之前也
little bit about um another thing that
稍微谈到了另一个话题，嗯，我之前也
has well we I kind of alluded to it that
略有提及，那就是自从
has emerged since you started writing
您开始写
this book which is the conversation
这本书以来出现的
around artificial intelligence. And when
关于人工智能的讨论。当
I start thinking about how you overlay
我开始思考如何将人工智能与
that with this idea of nuclear war, it
核战争的概念联系起来时，它
becomes even more um concerning because
变得更加令人担忧，因为
we're heading towards a world of what
我们正走向一个所谓的通用
intelligence where a lot of these
人工智能（AGI）的世界，在这个世界里，许多
systems will be making autonomous
系统将能够自主
decisions. they'll be able to and a
决策。
couple of people that I've spoken to
我曾与 DeepMind 或 Google 的几位人士交谈过，他们谈到，在这样
talked to me about a world where this is
一个世界里，虽然这只是
an extreme case but our elected leaders
一个极端情况，但我们选出的领导人要么
will be either AI themselves or being
本身就是人工智能，要么
basically working in lock step with AI
基本上与人工智能紧密合作。
and and then when you think about our
想想我们的
nuclear weapon systems who is better to
核武器系统，谁更适合
make that decision is it a Joe Biden
做这个决定？是乔·拜登，
launch a nuclear weapon or is it some
还是某种
so advanced
先进到
we might not even know what it's
我们甚至都不知道它在
thinking or doing. Have you thought much
想什么、在做什么的人工智能？自从
about artificial intelligence since this
这
book came out and since you started
本书出版，自从你开始
writing?
写作以来，你有没有认真思考过人工智能？
Absolutely. It's something I covered at
当然。我在《五角大楼
length in the Pentagon's brain, which is
的大脑》（一本关于美国国防高级研究计划局的书）中对此进行了深入探讨。
the book about DARPA. And I think that
我想，
maybe I'll speak to an origin story
或许我可以在这里谈谈它的起源
here, right? Because I think of
，对吧？因为我想到
Shakespeare, it's like what is past is
莎士比亚，就像过去是
prologue. We can understand better the
序幕。我们就能更好地理解
question you raised, especially for
你提出的问题，尤其是对
younger people, like what is this going
年轻人来说，比如
to look like in the future? Is a
未来会是什么样子？
president really going to be working in
总统真的会
consort with AI? If we know, wait, how
与人工智能合作吗？如果我们知道，等等，
did this all begin? It somehow, at least
这一切是如何开始的？至少在
to my eye, becomes easier to think about
我看来，这让我们更容易
these things in a grounded manner.
以一种务实的方式思考这些问题。
And so, I'll throw this detail at you.
所以，我再补充一点。
In in reporting the Pentagon's brain, it
在撰写《五角大楼的大脑》
was fascinating to learn that during
时，我发现一个非常有趣的现象：
World War II, computers were people.
二战时期，计算机指的是人。
A computer was someone who computed
计算机指的是进行数学运算的人
mathematical, you know, call
，比如弹道
trajectories, bomb explosions were all
轨迹、炸弹爆炸等，这些都由
measured by people and pencils
人用铅笔
and right. So then, and I love the smile
等工具进行测量。后来，我喜欢你脸上的笑容，
because suddenly it all becomes easier.
因为一切突然变得简单了。
Then you have a guy called John vonoman,
然后出现了一个叫约翰·冯·诺曼的人，他是
the f the the Pentagon's brain. He was
五角大楼的“大脑”。他是
the first brain that the Pentagon really
五角大楼真正
was interested in. And he created one of
感兴趣的第一个“大脑”。他创造了
the first computers. You can't really
最早的计算机之一。你不能把
assign the first computer to anyone, but
第一台计算机的真正归属归于任何人，但确实有
there was a computer that was doing
一台
calculations for called ENIAC. And
名为ENIAC的计算机在进行计算。
ultimately after the war, von Noman went
最终，战后，冯·诺曼
to the Atomic Energy Commission, the
找到了当时
most powerful organization in the world
世界上最有权势的机构——原子能委员会
at the moment, and said, "I want to
，他说：“我想
build a computer that can actually think
制造一台能够
for itself that can he he's kind of the
独立思考的计算机，一台能够……”他可以说是
progenitor of this idea of software, not
软件（而不仅仅是硬件）理念的先驱
just hardware." So for a long time, it
。因此，很长一段时间里，
computing, almost just like a giant
计算机都类似于德州仪器公司生产的那种，几乎就像一个巨大的
calculator. And Vonoyman
计算器。冯·诺曼
wanted to put the brain inside the
想要把“大脑”装进
calculator
计算器里，
and they gave him a lot of money to do
他们给了他一大笔钱来实现这个目标。
it. And he did this in the basement of
他
Fooled Hall over at the Princeton
在普林斯顿
Institute for Advanced Study. And it was
高等研究院的愚人楼地下室里完成了这项工作。那里有
giant vacuum tubes and he would do these
巨大的真空管，他会在那里进行各种
tests. And I describe this in the
测试。我之所以用
Pentagon's brain because it's really
五角大楼的大脑来描述这一切，是因为
interesting to think this was only in
想到这仅仅是
1945.
1945年，就让人觉得非常有趣。当时有
There were vacuum tubes and you know
真空管，还有
cords and they had to worry about mice
电线，他们还得担心老鼠会
eating cords. And John vonoyman was so
啃咬电线。约翰·沃诺曼非常
brilliant and smart that his he could
聪明，
beat the computer initially. The his
一开始他甚至能战胜计算机。他的
assistants would give him numerical
助手会给他一些数值
calculations. He would do them in his
计算题，他会在
mind. The computer would be trying to do
脑海中完成。计算机也会尝试
them. He would win. And then one day in
计算，但他总是赢。然后有一天，大概是
like I think it was 1946 or 1947 the
1946年或1947年，
computer beat him.
计算机击败了他。
That was the moment that vonoman
那一刻，沃诺曼
realized computers are going to be
意识到计算机将会变得
computers just got smarter than me than
比他更聪明，比
man. And then he began to develop and
人类更聪明。之后，他开始开发计算机
systems. The defense department began to
系统。国防部开始
into computer systems. And if you really
在计算机系统上投入巨资。如果你
want to know where they took off because
想知道这些系统是如何发展起来的，因为
this has to do with AI. This is man
这与人工智能有关，也就是
computer interface. The defense
人机交互。
department hires a guy called Licklider
国防部 他们雇佣了一个叫利克利德的人，
to essentially shrink computers down
让他把计算机
from the size of a house to the size of
从房子那么大缩小到
this room and think of what they are
这个房间那么大，然后思考它们现在是什么样子
now.
。
So the defense department has always led
所以国防部一直以
with artificial intelligence which is
人工智能为主导，而人工智能是基于
computerbased
计算机的。
and when you can see that origin story
当你了解了它的起源故事，
you can begin to understand where we're
你就能开始理解我们
going. and AI had to have these military
未来的发展方向。人工智能的发展离不开
the the benefits of these military
这些军事
systems to develop, right? Like
系统带来的好处，对吧？比如
nanotechnology.
纳米技术。
Things had to start becoming smaller.
事物必须开始变得更小。所有这些都
And that all happens in that book, you
在那本书里有所体现，当然
know, not all of it, but in other words,
不是全部，但换句话说，
you can you can learn in a sort of
你可以以一种
poetic manner the trajectory of
诗意的方式了解计算机的发展轨迹，
computers and where they began not so
以及它们
long ago and where we are now. And it
不久前的起源和我们现在的处境。
was in 1983 that DARPA, that
1983年，美国国防高级研究计划
organization, decided that the battle
局（DARPA）决定
place, the battlefield is no place for
，战场不适合
humans. That was a statement of its
人类。这是他们
first robotic AI program. I went on chat
第一个机器人人工智能项目的宣言。
PT um a couple of months ago and I asked
几个月前，我在聊天室PT上问过，
it I said could you play out a scenario
你能设想一下
where the world ends because an
世界末日的情景吗？因为
artificial intelligence basically gets
人工智能从
that it was um born out born on and it
它诞生的计算机中泄露出来。
the scenario that it played out involved
场景设定涉及
nuclear war because halfway I think it
核战争，因为我记得好像是
was in step three or four it says that
在第三步或第四步，
the AI basically takes control of the
人工智能控制了
nuclear warheads
核弹头，
or at least some of them and then it
或者至少控制了一部分，然后向
kind of launches them other countries
其他国家发射。
hearing Chachi PT
听Chachi PT
say that and and it and in step three or
这么说，而且在第三步或
four use nuclear weapons as a way to
第四步中，人工智能使用核武器来
kind of make the world extinct it it
毁灭世界，
felt plausible.
感觉挺有道理的。
Okay, so I'm going to push back against
好吧，我要反驳一下，
that and which is by no means right. I'm
这绝对不对。我
not but we're just having a like sort of
不是在胡说，我们只是在进行一些
theoretical conversation here.
理论探讨。Chat
Chat GPT is gathering its information,
GPT正在收集信息，
right? So my I would argue that Chhat GP
对吧？所以我认为Chat GPT
has got a lot of information from the
从《终结者》电影中获取了很多信息
Terminator movie.
。是的。
Yeah.
好吧。
Okay. There is that in the zeitgeist of
这在当时的社会思潮中确实存在
what happens. Then I want you to
。然后我想请你
consider that the communication systems
考虑一下
in nuclear command and control which is
核指挥控制系统（
actually nuclear command control and
实际上是核指挥控制与
communication. The the ability to for
通信系统）的通信能力。NC3
NC3 to communicate with the actual
与实际
weapons is so profoundly classified that
武器通信的能力属于高度机密，
I don't have access to it. But I'm going
我无法获取相关信息。但我会
to give this to you as an idea. What I
告诉你…… 一个想法。我在
do know and learned reporting nuclear
报道核
war scenario was a fascinating detail
战争场景时了解到，一个引人入胜的细节
that stands as an analogy at least for
至少对我来说可以作为类比
me, which is how analog
，那就是
our ballistic missile systems are
我们的弹道导弹系统与核战争有多么相似，
because of the exact fear that you
原因正是你所
describe or that and that chat GPT
描述的那种恐惧，或者说，GPT
described back at you. And will they
之前跟你提到的那种恐惧。它们
stay that way forever? Probably not. But
会永远如此吗？可能不会。但
are they that way right now? From what I
它们现在就是这样吗？据我
understand, yes. Our submarine launched
所知，是的。我们的潜艇发射
ballistic missiles that that are just so
弹道导弹，其
the technology behind them and I I
背后的技术非常先进，我来
delineate it for the reader. You it's
为读者详细解释一下。
missile from underwater. It can breach
从水下发射导弹，这令人震惊。它可以突破
the surface. It's after burners take off
水面，启动加力燃烧室，
and then it begins its trajectory, you
然后开始飞行，你
know, boost phase, midcourse phase,
知道，包括助推段、中段、末段，
terminal phase hits the target. This is
最终击中目标。这太
incredible. And how does it get there?
不可思议了。它是如何到达那里的呢？
You might ask, I asked. It gets there by
你可能会问，我也问了。它是通过
star sighting.
星体瞄准到达的。
Oh, really?
哦，真的吗？
So, you realize there's this little
你知道
panel that opens up in the ballistic
弹道导弹上有一个可以打开的小面板
missile. And there are other ways that
。它还有其他
it's navigating, but the primary mean of
导航方式，但主要的
navigation is star sighting, right? I
导航方式是星体瞄准，对吧？ 我的
mean, you just have to really stop and
意思是，你真的需要停下来好好想想
go, oh my. First of all, it's actually a
，我的天哪。首先，这确实是一个
really interesting concept that the most
非常有趣的概念：最
advanced potentially civilization ending
先进的、可能毁灭文明的
ballistic missile is guiding itself to
弹道导弹竟然是用
its target by this ancient concept like
这种古老的概念来引导自己击中目标
that. Our huntergather ancestors used
。我们的狩猎采集祖先就使用过这种方法——
which is looking at the stars.
观测星辰。
It's looking at the stars and then
它通过观测星辰来
navigating using them.
导航。
And that's meant to be
而这原本是为了
a defense against a system, an enemy
防御敌方系统
taking control of your nuclear weapons.
控制你的核武器。
The the issue we have is that there's
我们现在面临的问题是，世界上
potentially nine or 10 different nuclear
可能有九到十个不同的
powers and they don't all have the same
核大国，而且它们的系统并不完全相同
system. So if a if we get to the point
。所以，如果我们真的发展到通用人工智能（
of AGI which a lot of people almost see
AGI）时代——很多人几乎把它看作是奇点——那么
as the um singularity almost you can't
我们就无法
see past that moment where there is a
预见未来会发生什么：在
new being amongst us that is capable of
我们之中会出现一种新的生命体，它能够比
more intelligently than humans. It knows
人类思考得更快、更全面、更智能。它知道
things we don't.
我们不知道的事情。
I think it might look at our systems as
我认为它可能会把我们的系统视为
child's play. Maybe not our systems but
儿戏。也许不是我们的系统，但
maybe it'll look at North Korea's
它可能会把朝鲜的
systems as child's play. It might be
系统视为儿戏。它或许
able to put that VCR into the system and
能够…… 把那台录像机放进系统里，
play out the nucleus simulation that
播放核模拟程序，让
tricks those people into believing
那些人误以为
they're being attacked in that.
自己正在遭受攻击。
Yes.
是的。
And so,
那么，现在
which is maybe time for the answer to
或许是时候回答
your question of should we be at zero,
你的问题了，我们应该保持零核武器吗
right? Yeah. So what you have presented
？是的。你刚才提出的观点，正是像
somebody like me writing a book that
我这样的人写这本书的意义所在——让像
somebody like you would read of a
你这样的
younger generation and begin having
年轻一代阅读，并开始
these conversations with their
与他们的
colleagues and their thought leaders and
同事、思想领袖以及那些可能
the people that could maybe influence
影响
public policy and saying well that would
公共政策的人展开讨论，然后说，这是
be a very good reason to have zero
一个很好的理由，让我们保持零
nuclear weapons or you know everybody
核武器，或者你知道，每个人都
gets 10. I'm making that up. But right
拥有10枚核武器。我这是在开玩笑。但是，
because if you have 12,500 nuclear
如果你拥有12500枚
weapons, it's better than 70,000, but
核武器，这总比70000枚要好，但对于
like you're talking about.
你所说的这种人工智能触发场景来说，数量还是太多了。
Are you optimistic?
你乐观吗？我乐观吗？
optimistic about I I am
我的
I mean I am an optimistic person by
意思是，我天生就是一个乐观的人，
nature and so
那么
do you think there will be a nuclear war
你认为人类历史上会发生核战争吗
in the course of humanity?
？
I wrote this book as the optimistic,
我写这本书的初衷就是作为一个乐观、
hopeful person that's saying, "Read this
充满希望的人，我想说的是：  “读完这篇文章，你会
and realize
意识到，
that a man-made problem has a man-made
人为的问题也需要人为的
solution."
解决方案。”
Earlier you talked about there being
你之前提到过后果
high consequence and low probability,
严重但概率很低，
but the more the years tick on, that
但随着时间推移，这种
probability increases by nature of there
概率自然会增加，因为总会有那么一个
being this mad king
疯王
that might at some point. So, you know,
在某个时候做出这种事。所以，你知道，我也是这么想的
and that's what I think. So, I was
。因此，我一直在
asking myself eventually if we if we
问自己，如果我们把时间
play this forward, I don't know, a
推移一
thousand years, what what is most likely
千年，最有可能
to cause the end of humanity? Is it a
导致人类灭亡的是什么？是不是某个地方有个
mad king somewhere who doesn't want
疯王，他不想让儿子继承王位？
that, you know, he realizes that he's
他意识到自己即将
going to either die, he's got cancer, he
死去，他得了癌症，或者其他
realizes that, you know, he's got some
什么
sickness and he doesn't really want the
病，他不想让
his son to take power. He starts getting
儿子掌权。他开始变得
a bit agitated. Maybe he has some kind
焦躁不安。也许他患有某种
of psychosis, schizophrenia, I don't
精神病，精神分裂症，我不
know. decides to in his dying days to
知道。他决定在临终前
let a couple of these things fly. Is
放出一些东西。
that eventually going to happen? The
这种情况最终会发生吗？
laws of probability, the laws of
概率法则，
averages say that the longer we're here,
平均法则告诉我们，我们存在的时间越长，这种可能性就
the longer we have these weapons, the
越大。 我们拥有这些武器，
higher the probability.
可能性就越高。
I mean, I leave that to people like you
我的意思是，这个问题留给像你这样的人去
to think about and talk about because I
思考和讨论，因为我自己也在思考和讨论，
do and I am fascinated that I find that
而且我很惊讶地发现，你这
people of your generation
一代人比我这
perhaps people of my generation and
一代以及更
older. Like that was not a mindset that
年长的人更常问这个问题。好像以前人们并没有这种想法，
had and talked about and I think that
也没有人谈论过这个问题，我认为这
has to do with the confluence of events
与
that you talk about. First of all,
你提到的各种事件的交汇有关。首先，
people are have access to information in
人们现在获取信息的
a manner they didn't you know 30 40
方式与30、40
years ago or it took a lot more effort
年前截然不同，以前获取信息需要付出更多努力。
and also that there are these incredible
其次，正如你所说，现在存在着一些令人难以置信的
new threats that you're talking about
新威胁，
that are that you cannot overlook and so
我们不能忽视它们。所以
you would think that it's time to kind
你会觉得，是时候……
of and I'm not a polyiana but you have
我不是个偏执狂，但你必须
to move away from seeing everyone and
摒弃把所有人、
everything as an enemy and moving toward
所有事都视为敌人的做法，转而接受有对手、有
opponents is you know very sportsmen
竞争者是正常的，就像很多运动员都有
have opponents, right? But everyone
对手一样，对吧？但如果每个人都
being an enemy and having, you know,
被视为敌人，而且
wars
战争
escalating around the world, it seems as
在世界各地不断升级，那么
if what you are saying is there has to
你所说的似乎意味着，我们必须进行
be a fundamental shift in what people
根本性的转变。 人们
are considering important.
认为什么重要。
But war has always existed and it's
但战争一直存在，它与
existed as long as humans have. So it
人类历史一样悠久。这
makes me think that war is just part of
让我觉得，战争只是
humans trying to coexist and all of the
人类试图共存的一部分，所有
things that are hardwired into us, our
根植于我们内心的东西——对
search for status and ego and
地位、自我、
reproduction and resources and survival
繁衍、资源和生存的追求——都会导致
result in war like they result in
战争，就像它们会导致
recessions. So I read a lot about the
经济衰退一样。所以我读了很多关于
origin of war like there it's a debate
战争起源的文章，这本身就是一个争论不休的话题，虽然
no one you know but it is discussed and
没人知道确切答案，但确实有人在讨论。
the anthropologists I think have the
我认为人类学家们
concepts around it which I'll share with
对这个问题提出了一些非常有趣且富有洞察力的观点，我会和
you which is this because yes
你们分享。因为从
technically meant there has always been
技术上讲，这意味着战争一直存在，
war and that one of the debates is you
而其中一个争论点就是……
know did war begin with civilization or
战争是随着文明的到来而开始的，还是
were hunter gatherers waring but more
狩猎采集者就开始交战了？但
interesting to that I think is about the
我认为更有趣的是，
anthropologists who studied in the 60s
20 世纪 60 年代，人类学家研究了
the hunter gatherer tribes like in the
亚马逊等地的狩猎采集部落，
Amazon when there were still access to
当时人们还能接触到
them and they were sort of, you know,
这些部落，
they were unaffected by civilization at
他们几乎没有受到文明的影响，因此人类学家
all and they could look at how they
可以观察他们是如何
perceived enemies. And an interesting
看待敌人的。 由此产生了一个有趣的
idea came out of that which makes me
想法，让我不禁
think about optimists versus pessimists,
思考乐观主义者和悲观主义者之间的区别，
right? or or rather those who trust
对吧？ 或者更确切地说，是信任他人的人与
versus those who are suspicious. That
多疑的人之间的对比。
and that no matter if a hunter is out
也就是说，无论猎人是在
hunting in a that's part of a hunter
狩猎
gatherer tribal environment and he comes
采集部落环境中外出狩猎，还是遇到了
across another person.
另一个人。
Obviously there could be that person is
显然，这个人
either threatening or that person is
要么是威胁者，要么是可以
someone to team up with against the
联手对抗
greater threat. And the anthropologists
更大威胁的人。 人类学家
do not know why it is that some people
也不知道为什么有些人会
interpret this person with suspicion and
怀疑这个人，甚至
then might kill him and others would
可能杀了他，而另一些人则会把这
interpret that person as a teammate.
个人视为队友。
And so if we don't know how human, you
所以，如果我们不知道人类的本质是什么，你
know, is it genetics, like how do people
知道，是基因决定的，比如人们是如何
either fall on one of those two sides?
分属这两个阵营之一的呢？
But what we do know is that people can
但我们确实知道，人们可以
learn to think differently. You talk
学会用不同的方式思考。 你
with half your guests on the podcast
在播客节目中会和一半的嘉宾谈论
about this. People can be trained, not,
这个话题。 人们可以被训练，不是被
you know, propagandized, but people can
灌输某种观念，而是可以
learn to think differently. So if you're
学会用不同的方式思考。 所以，如果你像
me who is a hopeful person and wants to
我一样，是一个充满希望的人，
see the positive side of even my dark
即使在我报道的负面新闻中也想看到积极的一面，
reporting because that's a better choice
因为这对
for me and for my family. I train myself
我和我的家人来说都是更好的选择。 我训练自己去
to find if you will the silver lining or
寻找一线希望，或者更确切地说，
rather if that's too polyiananish to
如果这太乐观了，那就去
find the way in which how do I look at
寻找一种方法，让我把迎面
the person coming at me as someone who
走来的人看作
could be on my team or even an an
可能是我的队友，甚至是
opponent but not an enemy that I would
对手，但不是我必须
have to kill.
杀死的敌人。   在
you've written about that we haven't
你写过的所有书中，最有趣的、我们还没有
discussed
讨论过的内容是什么？
of all and I don't just mean in the
我指的不仅仅是关于
nuclear war I mean in all these books. I
核战争的内容，而是指你所有的著作。 我的
mean, I'm particularly fascinated by
意思是，我对DARPA特别感兴趣，
DARPA because I think in a lot of the
因为我认为在
world, especially in Europe, in the UK,
世界上很多地方，尤其是在欧洲和英国，
we we don't even know what DARPA means.
我们甚至不知道DARPA是什么意思。
So, you it was interesting reading about
所以，读到关于
the existence of that. But in all these
它的存在，感觉很有意思。 但是，在所有这些
books, what is the most interesting
书中，最有趣
thing, the most resonant thing when you
、最能引起人们共鸣的是什么？当你
talk about your work to people? Maybe
和别人谈论你的作品时，是什么？ 或许
that surprised you.
这让你感到惊讶。
I mean, every single one of my books is
我的意思是，我的每一本书
powerfully important to me, not just
对我来说都意义非凡，不仅是
because of the information there, but
因为书中的信息，更是
because of the people I met along the
因为我在写作过程中遇到的人
way. And I really could not si, you
。 我真的不能，你
know, put one over the other because
知道，把其中一个放在另一个之上，因为
that would be like favoring a child. And
那就像偏袒一个孩子一样。
I mean that literally, you know, that
我的意思是，真的，你知道，
sometimes when I prepare to do a
有时候我准备做
podcast, I read my own books and I and
播客的时候，我会读自己的书，对我来说，
I'm really it for me it's the it's the
这真的是我
incredible fortune of interviewing and
采访过的这些非常迷人的人的总和，以及
also how fate and circumstance always
命运和境遇似乎总是在
seems to play a role in all of their
他们的生活中扮演着某种角色
lives. And that's maybe the theme that I
。 这或许是我从这一切中
take away from all of this as opposed to
得到的启示，而不是具体的令人
the specific shocking thing because
震惊的事情，因为
remember that many of the people that I
请记住，我采访的许多人都是
interview because they're war fighters
战士
or intelligence agency people, many of
或情报机构人员，
their friends have died.
他们的许多朋友都已去世。   在
Is there anyone you interviewed that
你采访过的所有人中，有没有哪位受访者在
interviewing them?
采访过程中让你感动落泪？
Oh, absolutely. I can't I can't even I
当然。 我不能，我甚至
can't even say it now because I might
现在都说不出口，因为我可能会……是的
Yeah.
。
I'm going to ask you for the example.
我要你举个例子。
You want the example? I'll tell you
你想听例子吗？ 我现在就告诉你
right now.
。
That's a hard one. Um,
这真是个难题。 嗯，
so I was just in
我刚才
I was just in uh Brussels, I told you,
在布鲁塞尔，我跟你说过，参加了
at the nuclear convention and
核能大会，在那里
and I met a woman who was one year and
我遇到了一位女士，长崎
10 months when the bomb was dropped on
原子弹爆炸时她才一岁零十个月
Nagasaki.
。
So, she's a survivor of the Nagasaki
所以，她是长崎
bomb,
原子弹爆炸的幸存者，
right?
对吗？
I met her. I brought her a signed copy
我遇见了她。 我给她带了一本
of my book, right? I mean, you just
我签名的书，对吧？ 我的意思是，你只要
think about being a victim of that. And
想想自己成为受害者会是什么感觉。
also, I learned so much about the stigma
此外，我还了解到很多关于广岛和长崎原子弹幸存者所遭受的污名化问题
Hiroshima Nagasaki. stigma because they
。 由于他们
were perceived as sort of
被视为某种受
tainted people, tainted humans, and
污染的人，受污染的人类，因此遭受了污名化，并且人们对
of radiation.
辐射的遗留问题深感恐惧。
I met her and I expected to just be so
我见到她时，本以为自己会非常
composed, but in talking to her, I got
镇定，但和她交谈后，我却变得
very emotional kind of, you know,
非常激动，你知道，
because you can't avoid that. And part
因为你无法避免这种情况。
of the reason why I got so emotional was
我情绪如此激动的部分原因是，
that, and I haven't written about this
虽然我还没有写过这件事
yet, but I will, is that someone I
，但我以后会写，那就是我采访过的一个人，
interviewed and someone that meant a lot
一个
to me and that I have written about a
对我意义重大、我写过很多关于他的文章的人，制造了
that was dropped on Nagasaki.
投在长崎的那枚核武器。
And so when you think about it,
所以当你仔细想想，
and there's little old me, the reporter,
我这个不起眼的小记者，
Brussels last week at a nuke expo, you
上周被命运和机缘巧合地派到了布鲁塞尔参加核能博览会，
couldn't make that up if you were me,
如果你是我，你绝对编不出这样的故事，
you know, even a year ago, let alone 10
你知道，即使是一年前，更不用说十年
years ago, let alone when I was a child.
前，更不用说我还是个孩子的时候了。
And here I am. And one hand of my
我来了。 我的
reporting goes to that source that
报道中，有一部分要归功于那位
worked with me for a very long time,
与我共事很长时间的消息人士，
whose story I haven't written yet, who
我还没有写出他的故事，他就是投掷
wired the bomb that was dropped on
在长崎的那颗炸弹的幕后策划者
Nagasaki. And my other hand goes to
。 我的另一只手伸向了当时在场的
someone who was there.
人。   这会让人
That that wells you up because it's the
热泪盈眶，因为这就是
human condition.
人类的境况。
Can you speak to this impact that
您能否谈谈这件事
that had on both those individuals?
对这两个人的影响？
So, starting with if we start with the
那么，就让我们从参与
individual who was involved in wiring
安装
that bomb.
炸弹的那个人开始说起吧。
Mhm.
嗯。
So, and I know less about her than I
所以，我对她的了解比
know about him. Right.
对他的了解还要少。 正确的。
and I've reached out to her and we will
我已经联系了她，我们
do interviews now. Okay. So, but for him
现在将进行采访。 好的。 但对他来说，
it impacted his whole life and he became
这件事影响了他的一生，他成为了
a member of the Manhattan Project and he
曼哈顿计划的一员，并与
became uniquely tied into the nuclear
核武器工业建立了独特的联系
weapons industry.
。
So, these kind of long arcs of history
所以，这种漫长的历史进程
are so deeply interesting to me,
对我来说非常有趣，
especially as I get older. you move from
尤其是随着年龄的增长。 你从
that people were on, of specific
人们执行的特定任务、
operations they ran. And you begin to
他们开展的特定行动的强度出发。 你会开始
look at a human
观察一个人的
over the course of their life and what
一生，以及这其中的
that means because ultimately that's the
意义，因为归根结底，这才是
most interesting storytelling of all.
最有趣的故事。
It's the most interesting conversation
这是你我之间最有趣的一次对话
you and I can have. and and you have to
。
get a little bit older to know that, you
你知道，你得年纪大一点才能明白这一点。
know, but sometimes when I'm
但有时候，当我
interviewing people who are in their 80s
采访那些八九
and 90s and I see them looking at me and
十岁的老人时，我看到他们看着我，
I like especially going back 15 years
尤其是回想15年前
ago when I started reporting all this
我开始报道这一切的时候，
and I could see I can you know they're
我能感觉到他们年纪大了，耳朵下垂，脸上布满了
have you know incredible wrinkles and
皱纹，
the course of their lives what they have
他们的人生轨迹，他们的经历，
done and they're all involved in these
他们都参与过这些
top formerly top secret programs
曾经是最高机密的项目。
And I can I can I sense them looking at
我能感觉到他们看着
me with this sense of their own legacy
我，带着一种他们自身使命的感慨，仿佛在说：
that they are like I'm telling her my
我正在讲述我的
story and then I'm going to be gone. And
故事，然后我就要离开了。
that's really that's powerful.
这才是真正强大的地方。
It's a lot of trust as well, isn't it?
这其中也包含着很大的信任，不是吗？   没错，这
It it is that's the role of the
就是记者的职责
reporter. you you work at least my job
。 至少我
as an investigative journalist is like
作为一名调查记者，我的工作就是希望
you know I want people to trust me that
人们信任我，相信
I am getting the in their information
我能把他们掌握的信息
down on the public record and that has a
公之于众。这很大程度上解释了
lot to do with why you know people say
为什么人们会问，你是
how did you get so many people to talk
怎么让这么多人跟你谈论
to you about nuclear weapons right so to
核武器的。所以，回到
loop this back to nuclear war scenario I
核战争的场景，我
know I'm doing my job at least it feels
知道我至少在认真履行我的职责，因为就
that I can in the same week last week
在上周，我能让
have two people that are 100% part of
两位完全属于
the military-industrial complex working
军工复合体、
for the Space Force in Los Angeles, you
在洛杉矶为太空部队工作的人，
know, at a Space Force convention, come
在太空部队大会上，来
to my house for dinner,
我家吃晚饭，
have a conversation with my family,
和我的家人聊天，
including my young son who's closer to
包括我那和
your age, and then the week before have
你年纪相仿的小儿子。而就在前一周，我还
been with peace activists
和和平活动
addressing members of the European
人士一起在欧洲
Parliament. I have my lane, but yet all
议会发表演讲。 我走的是自己的路，但周围却围着
of these people are around me.
这么多人。
They might not think they can get along,
他们或许认为彼此相处不来，
but they probably can. And if I'm the
但实际上他们很可能可以。 如果我在这三者之间保持中立
middle of the road of all of that, that
，这
is important to me as an investigative
对我来说很重要，因为我既是一名调查
journalist and but also like as an
记者，又是一名
American citizen as and as I said
美国公民，而且正如我
earlier as a as a mother.
之前所说，我还是一位母亲。
bomb took part in the Manhattan Project
参与曼哈顿计划并安装炸弹的人，就是
lady that you met recently.
最近向你遇到的那位女士投掷炸弹的人。
How do they feel about that now in
现在回想起来，随着年龄的增长，他们对此有何感想
they look back?
？
He has died. Oh, okay.
他去世了。 哦好的。
He has died. Um,
他去世了。 嗯，
how did he feel about it?
他对此有何感想？
There were other things that bothered
还有其他一些事情更让
him more, which is
他困扰，那就是
using your own eyes to
用自己的眼睛去
perceive another person. And it's why I
感知另一个人的巨大难题。 这就是为什么我
have not written that book yet because
还没有写那本书的原因，因为
it is still very confusing and there is
它仍然非常令人困惑，而且其中有
a lot of mysterious elements of it.
很多神秘的元素。
Sometimes when people are involved in
有时，当人们参与到
really classified programs, you have to
高度机密的项目中时，你必须
spend a lot of time to uh
花费大量时间去
dig and uncover and discover. It's a
挖掘、揭露和发现。 这是一个
long process. Um and he was involved in
漫长的过程。 嗯，他还参与了
some other programs that he had more
一些其他项目，他对这些项目有更
intense thoughts about. And that alone
深入的思考。 光这一点就
is enough to I mean the look on your
足以说明问题了，我的意思是，你脸上的表情和我
interviewing him.
采访他时的表情一模一样。
A happy man.
一个快乐的人。
Absolutely. Absolutely.
绝对地。 绝对地。
Regret.
后悔。   是的
Yes. Most definitely. Almost everyone
。 当然。 几乎所有
that I end up spending hours and hours
我会一起旅行，并且最终会花好几个小时相处的人
and hours with that I would travel with.
。
And you know another person that comes
你知道吗，我脑海中浮现的另一个人
to mind was Billy Wall in the Surprise
是《突袭、
Kill Vanish book. Sort of the longest
杀戮、消失》这本书里的比利·沃尔。 他算是
serving singleton for the US government
美国政府服役时间最长的
as a paramilitary operator. The saying
准军事特工之一。 俗话说
goes, "Billywah killed more people than
，“比利瓦杀的人比癌症杀的人还多
cancer."
。”
Okay. We traveled to Hanoi together. We
好的。 我们一起去了河内。 我们
traveled to Havana together. Um, I spent
一起去了哈瓦那。 嗯，我
a lot of time with him. Uh, they were,
和他相处了很长时间。 呃，
you know, both of these men were
你知道，这两个人
probably the two most powerful sources I
可能是我一生中合作过的最有影响力的两个人，当时他们都
90s.
八九十岁了。
Both happy men.
两个都很快乐的人。
Billy was more complex than happy, you
你知道，比利这个人很复杂，并不快乐
know.
。
um
嗯，
you work hard to kind of get at the
你努力去
to get at the character of someone and
了解一个人的性格，你
you you you you try the best to
尽力去
represent them. But I mean, you know,
展现他们。 但我的意思是，你知道，
Billy had so many people um he was
比利参与
involved in so many missions with so
过很多任务，
many people that died that I don't know
很多战友牺牲了，我不知道他是否
if happiness is he certainly wasn't an
快乐，他肯定不是快乐的人，
he certainly wasn't sour, but uh he had
他肯定也不是怨恨的人，但是他
a lot of anger about a lot of things.
对很多事情都充满了愤怒。
And then the lady, she was one and a
而那位女士，
half years old when the bomb was
炸弹落下时她才一岁半
dropped. She survived as a baby.
。 她婴儿时期活了下来。
Her family, did they survive?
她的家人幸存下来了吗？   是的
Yes. And it was it's fascinating. Um
。 这真是太精彩了。 嗯……
uh I'm not saying her name because I
我
don't I I don't have quite her
还没得到她的
permission yet. Right. So, but um
许可，所以暂时不说她的名字。 正确的。 所以，
although she is a public figure, but she
虽然她是一位公众人物，但
didn't know about her story until she
直到长大后她才知道自己的故事，
got older because it was kept hidden
因为这些故事一直
from her, which is so these layers upon
对她隐瞒着，这就是
layers about what we know about our own
我们对自身了解的层层迷雾
selves. You've made me think of which is
。 你让我想到，
you balance that out with
你要如何平衡
qu what you know about your own self
你对自己的了解与
versus what how easy it is to to judge
评判他人
someone else or perceive someone else.
或感知他人是多么容易之间的矛盾呢？
And I think those two journeys in life
我认为人生中的这两段旅程
are interwoven always like our own
总是交织在一起的，就像我们自己的
journey for self-discovery, right? In a
自我发现之旅一样，对吗？ 从
way, you're on that with your podcast.
某种意义上说，你的播客也正是如此。
I'm guessing you probably learn as much
我猜你
about yourself um as you do about
对自己的了解可能和对
others. I know I do. I'm usually in your
别人的了解一样多。 我知道我会。 我通常坐在你的
seat.
位置上。
Um and there's no camera running. It's
嗯，而且没有摄像头在运行。 这
just a pen. And so I can learn so much
只是一支笔。 因此，我可以从
from people about how they speak, why
人们的说话方式、
they speak, what they say to me. I don't
说话原因以及他们对我说的话中学到很多东西。 我不想把这件事记录在案
want this on the record. I want you to
。 我想让你
know this about me because it's
知道我的这件事，因为它很
important, but I don't want it publicly
重要，但我不想让它
known. And I honor that because in a way
公之于众。 我尊重这一点，因为从某种意义上说，
being a journalist is being a a trusted
作为一名记者，就是成为一个值得信赖的信息
source that someone can
来源，人们可以在我
that the person i.e. me knows the
（记者）了解的
groundwork about. Many people's
背景范围内与我分享信息。 很多人的
grandchildren's
孙子
grandchildren don't they don't know what
孙女都不知道
grandpa did and they might not know for
爷爷做过什么，而且可能几十年都不知道
decades. I had a guy show up at one of
。 就在上周日，我在洛杉矶时报书展的签售会上遇到了一位男士，
Sunday and he had, you know, a binder
他带着一个活页夹，
and he said, "After you're done signing,
他说：“签完名后，
would you mind looking at this binder
您能否看一下这个活页夹，
and interpreting it for me?" And of
并帮我翻译一下？”
course I did, you know, and his
当然，我的确知道，他的
grandfather was a seriously high ranking
祖父是一位级别很高的
person working on nuclear sublaunched
人物，
ballistic missiles in the early days of
在早期
what was called the Polaris experiment.
被称为“北极星”实验的核潜射弹道导弹项目中工作。
And he had all these documents and no
他手里拿着所有这些文件，但
one in his family cared about it. He had
他的家人却没有人关心。 他有身份
ID badges and letters and pictures with
识别徽章、信件、与
the president and picture and I could
总统的合影等等，我可以
say to him, "Oh yes, this is the," you
对他说：“哦，是的，这就是……”，你
know, I could give him some context and
知道，我可以给他一些背景信息，
his wife was there and you know, it was
他的妻子也在那里，你知道，这就是
just like it's a great example of how we
一个很好的例子，说明我们
sometimes have a desire to know about
有时多么渴望了解
our own selves and our own legacy. Where
自己和自己的遗产。
did we come from? And then grandpa has
我们从哪里来？ 然后，爷爷
passed. And so my job is like getting
去世了。 所以，我的工作就像是把
grandpa's story on the record.
爷爷的故事记录下来。
that conversation you had um since the
自从这
book had come out with the lady you met
本书出版以来，你和你
in Brussels,
在布鲁塞尔遇到的那位女士进行了一次谈话，这次谈话
did it change how you viewed your your
是否改变了你对这
book and the work you've done here
本书以及你
in writing this? Did it add an element?
在写作过程中所做的工作的看法？ 它添加了元素吗？
Oh, it most certainly enhanced and added
哦，它确实增强并增添了，
and particularly that emotional one that
特别是
you saw for me when I think about that,
当我想到这件事时，你看到的那种情感上的感受，
you know. Um
你知道的。 嗯，
and I immediately had a long
我回家后立刻就
conversation with my husband about it
和丈夫就此事进行了长时间的谈话
when when I got home, right? because I
，对吧？ 因为我需要通过
use sounding boards to understand how I
倾听和交流来了解自己
even really feel about things. But I
对事物的真实感受。 但我
already had a context to know about
之前已经对
survivors having read a lot of accounts
幸存者有所了解，因为我阅读了很多幸存者的叙述，
to report the book and I mention
为撰写这本书做准备，我在书中提到了其中一些
some of them. Satsuko Thurlo was a
。 萨苏科·瑟洛是
survivor of Hiroshima and has given a
广岛原子弹爆炸的幸存者，她曾
the record to the United Nations and
在联合国和
elsewhere. And I quote her in my book to
其他场合发表过许多令人难以置信的公开声明。 我在书中引用了她的话来
narrate the part of the story where we
叙述故事中
learn about the bomb dropping on
关于广岛原子弹爆炸的那部分
Hiroshima. And then I read a lot of the
。 然后我阅读了很多相关的
ancillary material about that so I can
辅助材料，以便
understand more and try and a lot of
更好地理解和尝试。
work as a journalist you're just at
作为一名记者，
least if you write narrative non-fiction
如果你像我一样撰写叙事性非虚构作品，
as I do you're really trying to imagine
你确实会努力想象当时的
the situation
场景，
but then you meet someone and it all
但当你遇到某个人时，一切都
becomes real
变得真实起来。
and that's where the this comes in
这就是问题的关键所在，
because it's not just words on the paper
因为这不仅仅是纸上的文字。
when they say a survivor
当他们说“幸存者”时，
what What how do you categorize or
你该如何定义或
define a survivor of a nuclear bomb?
界定核弹幸存者呢？
I'm there's a word in Japanese and I
我知道日语里有个词，我
don't want to get it wrong and it's
不想说错，它是不是类似
something like hibaka, right? So,
hibaka之类的，对吧？ 所以，
forgive me for not having that word, but
请原谅我没有那个词，但是，
um that is an actual term that is used
嗯，这是一个真实存在的术语，
by anyone who
任何
lived through the atomic bombings in
经历过
August of 1945 of Hiroshima and
1945 年 8 月广岛和
Nagasaki.
长崎原子弹爆炸的人都会使用这个词。
So, if you lived through it, you are in
所以，如果你经历过那段时期，你就是
that category of people. And most of the
那类人之一。 而且大部分都是“是的”
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. And so in other words
。 是的。 是的。 换句话说，
now uh this was you know 79 years ago.
这已经是79年前的事了。
So most of the survivors you can just
所以大多数幸存者，你只要
think about the ages of the people
想想相关人员的年龄就行了
involved. Suko Thurlo is 90. You know,
。 苏科·瑟洛今年90岁了。你知道，
she's she's won she was a recipient of
她曾获得过我
the who I who I write about. Um she was
笔下人物奖。 嗯，她
2017 with a group of physicians,
与一群医生，包括
Dr. Carlos Omana and others whom I met
卡洛斯·奥马纳博士和其他我
in Brussels that are all part of these
在布鲁塞尔遇到的医生，共同获得了 2017 年诺贝尔和平奖，他们都是致力于将
organizations working to reduce nuclear
核武器减少
weapons down to zero. Right? They are
到零的组织的成员。 正确的？ 他们
against nuclear war and their
反对核战争，他们的
organizations work diligently to bring
组织努力将
the information to the four and to
信息传递给四方，并在
like the United Nations.
联合国等地缘政治层面上影响变革。
husband when you get home that day after
你那天回家后和丈夫进行的那次谈话，就是你和
meeting her.
她见面之后的那次谈话。
What can you tell me about that
你能告诉我一些关于那次
conversation?
谈话的内容吗？
It's probably like you have with your I
这可能就像你和我丈夫的情况一样，我的
mean my husband and I have been married
意思是，我和我丈夫结婚
a very long time so he knows everything.
很久了，所以他什么都知道。   还有
Um there's also a joke that he has
一个笑话说他有
what's called spouse privilege which he
所谓的配偶特权，
does right you can tell your spouse
没错，你可以合法地告诉你的配偶
anything legally.
任何事情。
But no those conversations are
但那些对话却​​是
priceless. Those are the conversations
无价之宝。 这些对话
that allow me to try and peel back one
让我有机会去揭开
layer of what the next book is going to
下一本书的面纱，了解它的内容
be and what the next book aims to do
和目标，
because I am always working on the next
因为我一直在创作下一
book. I am one of those people who loves
本书。 我热爱
writing and so and I also love evolving
写作，也热爱不断提升自己的
as a writer. So you want to get better
写作水平。 所以，你想
in terms of the small mistakes you make
在减少小错误方面有所进步，
and you want to get better in terms of
也想在表达主题意图方面有所进步
thematically about conveying it. And so
。 所以，
thank you for pointing out to me and I
谢谢你指出这一点，我是
mean this sincerely is that what you
真心实意的，你
helped me realize is that the next book
帮助我意识到，下一本书
is trying will try to move more toward
将会尝试更多地朝着“
those themes of cause that was him and
他是原因，她
effect that was her. this idea that
是结果”这个主题发展。 这种想法认为，任何事情都有
there are always consequences
后果，
and very real people on both sides that
双方都有非常真实的人，
you know one could class as both victims
你可以把他们同时归类为受害者
and innocent at the same time I guess of
和无辜者，我想这
just a horrific situation.
只是一场可怕的事件。
Absolutely.
绝对地。
I'm really intrigued now by this idea
我现在对“
that you almost have to embody two
你几乎必须扮演两个
roles. You're a human being,
角色”这个想法非常感兴趣。 你是一个人，
but at the same time you've got a job to
但同时你也有工作要做，
do here and you've got a mission. And
你肩负着使命。
when you meet that person who is who is
当你遇到一位
a survivor of a nuclear attack, those
核袭击的幸存者时，这些
lines can understandably become at least
界限很容易
in your head, the wall can drop between
在你脑海中消失，两人之间的隔阂也会随之消除
the two. And as you you touched your
。 当你抚摸自己的
heart, you referred to your head, which
心时，你提到了你的头，
I think is typically when you're talking
我认为这通常是在谈论
about your journalistic hat, but then we
你的记者身份，但
all have hearts as well, thank God. Um,
谢天谢地，我们所有人都有心。 嗯，
you come home and I know the
你回家后，我知道
conversations I have with my partner. I
我和伴侣的对话。 我
guess I'm assuming you know the
猜你应该知道
conversation you have with your husband
你和你丈夫在那里进行的对话
there is about
是关于
the complexity of the emotions you feel
你
upon meeting that person.
见到那个人时所感受到的复杂情感。
Absolutely. And what you do with that
绝对地。 而你如何处理这些，
and what that means and you want to be
以及这些意味着什么，你都希望
able to have those conversations so that
能够进行这些对话，这样
you can I think
你就可以
have both of those bring both of those
把这两个
components into your into your work. I
方面都融入到你的工作中。 我的
mean, maybe with the exception being the
意思是，也许除了
military or the CIA, the two
军队或中央情报局这两个
organizations I write about, you know,
我描写的组织之外，你知道，
Billy W can't bring his heart into the
比利·W在
mission when he is assigned to go XYZ,
被指派去执行XYZ任务时，比如
you know, find, fix, and finish someone.
找到、解决并消灭某人，就无法全身心投入到任务中。
partners, are they, in the CIA? No.
在中央情报局，他们不允许告诉他们的搭档，对吧？ 不。
From what I told you
就我跟你说的，
and and so so what we that aren't in the
我们这些不在
military or the intelligence community
军队或情报部门的人就
have that luxury. Is it a luxury? I
没有这种奢侈了。 这是奢侈品吗？ 我
don't know. But it's a necessity for me.
不知道。 但对我来说，这是必需的。
What if you couldn't?
如果你做不到呢？
I wouldn't be myself. I wouldn't I
我会不再是我自己。 我不会，我
wouldn't choose that. I could never be
不会选择那个。 我永远不可能
in the military. I could never be in the
参军。 我永远不可能加入那个
agency because I I think you are asked
机构，因为我觉得在那里你会被要求
to wear a hat that removes your heart.
戴上一顶会掏空你内心的帽子。
And that's not possible for somebody
而像
like me. I mean, we just figure out our
我这样的人是做不到的。 我的意思是，我们只需要弄清楚自身的
strengths and our weaknesses. Um, and
优势和劣势。 嗯，
society needs all of those people. By
社会需要所有这些人。
the way, that is what a democracy is. It
顺便说一句，这就是民主的本质。 它
is made up of all kinds of people. I'm
由各种各样的人组成。 我完全赞成
all for that. It's why I have so many
。 这就是为什么我有很多
friends and colleagues from different
来自不同
worlds on different sides of the aisle.
领域、不同政治立场的朋友和同事。
They just make me think more interesting
它们让我思考更多
things about the world in which we all
关于我们共同生活的世界的有趣问题
live.
。
We have a closing tradition on this
我们这个播客有个结尾的传统，
podcast where the last guest leaves a
最后一位嘉宾会给下一位嘉宾留下一个
question for the next guest not knowing
问题，但他并不知道这个问题是
who they're leaving it for. And the
留给谁的。
question that's been left for you was
留给你的这个问题，是
written in Europe when we're over in our
我们在欧洲的
studio there.
工作室里写下的。
It is, what is the last thing you
没错，你最近一次
changed your mind about?
改变主意是什么时候？
Well, I'll just it comes this comes to
嗯，我之所以想到这件事，是
mind only because it's apppropo to what
因为它与
we've been talking about and it has to
我们一直在谈论的话题相关，而且它
do with reporting, not my personal life,
与新闻报道有关，与我的个人生活无关，而我的个人生活
which is maybe more interesting to
可能更受
people. Um,
人们关注。 嗯，
I always strive to interview people and
我总是努力采访别人，
ask them questions even if they're hard,
问他们问题，即使这些问题很难回答，
even if I have a preconception that
即使我先入为主地认为
maybe they are the sort of bad guy,
他们可能是那种坏人，
shall we say, or the, you know,
或者，你知道的，
perpetrator,
罪犯，
the what?
什么？   做某事的
The perpetrator of
人
some something, not necessarily the, but
，不一定是本人，但就像
just that like I I might not my brain
我一样，我的大脑
might not think I agree with what they
可能不会认为我同意他们
did or the project they were on. And
所做的事情或他们正在进行的项目。
there was a general that I was trying to
我当时正在采访一位将军，想让他担任
interview for the Pentagon's brain. And
五角大楼的智囊。 而且
he had he was kind of the creator behind
他可以说是
what's called the soldier super suit.
所谓“士兵超级战衣”背后的创造者。
Okay? And that's a totally different
好的？ 那完全是另一个
subject. But that these idea to make
话题了。 但是，这些制造
super soldiers, okay? Off of this idea
超级士兵的想法，可以吗？ 基于
of the this concept called the weakling
这种被称为
on the battlefield that humans feel fear
战场上弱者的概念，人类会感到恐惧
and get fatigued and those are not good
和疲惫，这
things for soldiers. And so there are
对士兵来说都不是好事。 因此，我们推出了
all these programs to try and enhance
各种计划，试图将
our top tier military fighters to become
我们最优秀的军事战士培养成
super soldiers. This is a fact. And this
超级士兵。 这是事实。 而这位
one general was part of that program.
将军正是该计划的参与者。
And I had reached out to him and asked
我联系了他，并邀请
him to interview with me. And I get it.
他接受我的采访。 我明白了。
Lots of people say and you know I'm
很多人都这么说，你知道我会
going to pass. I don't want to
放弃的。 我不想
interview. That's fine. But he ignored
面试。 没关系。 但他无视了
me and I felt slighted. And so I'm
我，我感到很受冷落。 所以，
telling on myself here from your view.
从你的角度来看，我这是在自曝其短。
And so when I was writing my narrative
所以，当我在创作
of the super soldier, he essentially was
关于超级士兵的故事时，他基本上被
kind of cast as the bad guy. And then
塑造成了一个坏人。 后来，
I was in the editorial phase of the book
我进入了这本书的编辑阶段，
and I got an email from him and he said,
收到了他的一封电子邮件，他说：
"I'm so sorry I didn't get back to you.
“非常抱歉我没有回复你。
My wife had cancer."
我的妻子得了癌症。”
And I What a valuable lesson. What a
多么宝贵的一课！ 多么
valuable lesson. and we did two
宝贵的一课！ 我们进行了两次
interviews and I told my editor I have
采访，我告诉我的编辑我必须
to rewrite that chapter and I did.
重写那一章，我也确实重写了。
I mean that story speaks to a lot of the
我的意思是，这个故事触及了
subjects we've spoken about today which
我们今天讨论的许多话题，那
is when we see someone as different when
就是当我们把某人视为异类，
we see them as aliens, adversaries,
视为外星人、对手、
enemies, opponents, we are much more
敌人、反对者时，我们更有
likely to treat them as such. But in
可能那样对待他们。 但
reality, it often turns out that we're
实际上，我们往往都
all very much the same, struggling with
大同小异，都在为
the same things, with the same worries,
同样的事情、同样的担忧、
anxieties, concerns, apprehensions. And
焦虑、顾虑和恐惧而苦恼。
it's just sometimes when there's a
有时候，当像
bridge built in the case of that email,
电子邮件那样搭建起沟通的桥梁时，
that we realize that we're not enemies
我们才会意识到我们终究不是敌人
after all, and that we don't need to be
，我们不需要
at war, whether that's with words or
开战，无论是用言语还是用
whether it's with nuclear weapons.
核武器。
And when you see that fellow hunter on
当你在路上遇到其他猎人时
the path,
，
they might not be the enemy. They might
他们可能并非敌人。 他们或许
be someone to work with.
是可以合作的对象。
Annie, because what you're actually
安妮，你能承认这一点非常好，因为你实际上
admitting is that you're a human being
承认了你是一个人，
because we all do that kind of thing.
因为我们都会做那种事。
When we see someone as an adversary, I
当我们把某人视为对手时，我
think, as you say, it's feels like it's
想，正如你所说，这感觉就像是
hardwired into us in some way. But also
我们与生俱来的某种本能。 但同时，
within that story, we learn to um to try
在这个故事中，我们也学会了尝试
and find or make the bridge ourselves,
自己去寻找或搭建桥梁，
which in the world we live in now with
这在我们如今生活的这个有
social media and stuff is doesn't seem
社交媒体等等的世界里，对于存在着各种两极分化等问题的人来说，似乎并不
to be um easy or obvious for people with
容易或显而易见
all of this polarization and such. And
。
maybe if the you know, if the US could
也许，如果美国能够
make a bridge with some of these foreign
与一些外国敌对国家建立联系
adversaries, we wouldn't be talking
，我们就不会像
about nuclear war in your book nuclear
你书中描述的那样讨论核
war scenario. Thank you so much for
战争了。 非常感谢你
writing this book because I'm a big
写了这本书，因为我
believer and a big um advocate of
坚信并大力倡导
confronting the realities honestly and
诚实、坦率地面对现实，
openly regardless of how uncomfortable
无论这有多么令人不舒服。
it is because if we don't I think it
因为如果我们不这样做，我认为
actually increases the probability of us
实际上会增加我们陷入
as you write about in the book and I the
你在书中描述的那种72小时困境的概率，而我，
same 72 minutes
72分钟，
72 minutes Jesus Christ 72 hours did I
72分钟，我的天哪，72小时，我
say 72 hours
说的是72小时吗？是的，
yes we all make Freudians okay I wish it
我们都成了弗洛伊德主义者，好吧，我希望
was 72 well no actually don't I'd ra it
是72小时，不，其实不是，我宁愿它真的会
was going to happen. I'd rather it just
发生。 我宁愿它就这么
happened in the blink of an eye. But um
一眨眼的功夫发生。 但是，嗯，
but no, I think it's it's so so
不，我认为
important to write. A lot of people will
写作非常非常重要。 很多人会
be scared. A lot of people have chosen
感到害怕。 很多人因为害怕讨论的内容，甚至选择
not to even click on this conversation
不点击进入这个对话
matter. But I I think it's leaning in
。 但我认为，积极参与
that helps us to um resolve and find
有助于我们解决问题、找到
solutions and start the conversation.
解决方案并开启对话。
And I know lots of people listen to
我知道很多人都在听
this. You never know like that um like
这个。 你永远无法预知，就像
that documentary or movie you talked
你之前提到的那部纪录片或电影里说的那样，
about earlier who's listening and the
谁在听，
powers that they have and the decisions
他们拥有怎样的权力，以及
that they can make to change things or
他们可以做出怎样的决定来改变现状，或者
to create one of those bridges to to
搭建一座桥梁，最终实现
sort of denuclearize the world and
世界无核化。而
that's the work you're doing. So I think
这正是你正在做的工作。 所以我认为
it's very very important work and I'm
这是一项非常非常重要的工作，我很
glad that you've um committed your
高兴你投入了你的
brilliance to doing it. So thank you.
才华去做这件事。 所以，谢谢你。
Thank you so much for having me.
非常感谢你们的邀请。
[Music]
[音乐]
Heat. Heat. N.
热浪。热。N.